<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://daniellytle.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://daniellytle.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-11-17T03:21:02-07:00</updated><id>https://daniellytle.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">daniellytle</title><subtitle>Write down three things you want to do, then do them</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Installing a Cheap (Amazon) Diesel Heater in my 2004 T1N Sprinter Van</title><link href="https://daniellytle.github.io/2023/03/06/installing-a-cheap-diesel-heater-in-my-2004-t1n-sprinter-van.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Installing a Cheap (Amazon) Diesel Heater in my 2004 T1N Sprinter Van" /><published>2023-03-06T16:23:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-03-06T16:23:00-07:00</updated><id>https://daniellytle.github.io/2023/03/06/installing-a-cheap-diesel-heater-in-my-2004-t1n-sprinter-van</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daniellytle.github.io/2023/03/06/installing-a-cheap-diesel-heater-in-my-2004-t1n-sprinter-van.html">&lt;p&gt;Heating a sprinter van in sub freezing temperatures is difficult, even if it’s insulated. Ideally you want something that is simple, cost-effective, and safe. I did a bit of research and talked to some van folks who suggested using Electric Blankets, Propane Space Heaters, and Diesel Heaters. I ended up trying all three of these options before ditching the rest for the diesel heater (it was by far the best solution).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the beginning…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general consensus in the van world is that diesel heaters are the best. There’s even a preferred van installation position and van shops are very familiar with the install job. I was a bit intimidated by the complexity of the install myself, I was still getting to know my van and nervous about drilling holes in the floor, so I figured I’d try some lower cost lower committement heating options before putting down serious time and money into the diesel heating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first weekend I tried the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mrheater.com/portable-buddy-heater.html&quot;&gt;Mr Buddy Heater&lt;/a&gt;, a classic portable space heater found at most big hardware stores. They burn small propane canisters which are also easy to find (also the ones you can use to hook up to camp stoves). A big issue with propane heaters is their exhaust must be vented. The propane reaction takes oxygen out of the air and replaces it with carbon monoxide (yikes). To be fair, the heater has a bunch of safety settings like an oxygen sensor and a tip-over auto shutoff, still I didn’t want to take any chances so I opened my roof fan and also had a carbon monoxide sensor with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results were ok. It was warmer than nights I had spent with no heating at all but certainly not the comfortable feeling I expected. The heat seemed to rise right up from the heater and out the vent. It’s possible I could have moved the heater further from the vent to spread the heat more evenly but I was worried about the flame and the fumes. On the low setting the heater lasted about 5 hours, forcing me to do a reluctant tank switch at 3am. It’s possible to hook these heaters to larger propane tanks but the idea of more gas inside or close to my living area didn’t appeal to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a buddy who swore by electric blankets and I happened to spot a whole shelf of them when walking through (where else but) Walmart. My friend had a well insulated camper and he’d use a wool blanket along with the electric blanket to stay warm. The next adventure weekend I gave it a try and was pleasently surprised. While taking a bit of time to learn the controls I found the blanket had the capacity to be too hot for me at higher settings, progress!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was sleeping on the electric blanket with a sleeping bag which trapped the heat well. The air however was still quite cold and the parts of the van away from the blanket were still very cold. This resulted in a very strong “I dont’ want to get out of bed” feeling. I figured these options wouldn’t cut it and it was time to take a crack at the diesel heater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About diesel heaters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of resources about diesel heaters online when I started looking. People use them for all sorts of applications: Garage heating, RV heating, Boat heating. They work by burning diesel fuel in a chamber that the heater blows air over. The exhuast is routed outside the space and you’re left with a hot dry stream of air. The benefits are pretty strong: Not having to deal with exhaust, the fuel consumption is very low, (in the case of diesel vehicles, the heater can source fuel directly from the main tank).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The diesel heater market is a bit strange. There are high end european heating units made by trusted companies like Espar and Eberspacher (1.5k - 2k), there are strangely branded options on amazong going for as low as $160, and there is nothing in between. As I am writing this I believe people are taking advantage of this gap and producing options a bit more appealing to the average american in the $500 range. Another peculiar bit about these two types of heater kits is that they look nearly identical, there’s hardly any difference in unit design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After waffling back and forth reading sequential reviews of: “This is great!”, “this is terrible”, I found an honest review with some wisdom, “Look it’s $160, if it breaks get another one”. This review spoke to me and I took a leap into the cheapo heater world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is your van compatible?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The heater I purchased was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08GHM583V/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; from a company called FIBERFLY (one of the more normal sounding of the bunch).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://m.media-amazon.com/images/I/71EFYGPDhYL._AC_SL1500_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Diesel Heater Kit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kit came with a fuel tank so worst case if I wasn’t able to tap into the main fuel tank I could mount this smaller fuel tank somewhere accessible. I needed to find out whether or not I could do the main fuel tank tap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking around online it’s understandable that everyone’s van is different, some models have extra fuel lines just for installing these heaters. I phoned a van shop and they told me to bring mine in so they could take a look at it. Within a few minutes of a guy looking underneath the van he had bad news. “Sorry man, there’s no auxiliary fuel tap, we’d have to lower the gas tank and empty it out to put one in”. The estimate for this work was incredible, around 4k. I was pretty dissapointed and started to think of where I was going to put this spare fuel tank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also a bit embarassed I knew so little about my own van but in my defense it was winter here in Colorado and crawling under a van on the side of the street did not sound fun. Even so it wore on me and I set out to learn more about my vehicle. I learned I have what’s know as a T1N Sprinter (2002-2006 production run). These models have similar build styles and accept similar parts. I also noticed there were a few tutorials for specific T1N van projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What really got me going was the realization that my van already had a small diesel heater, meant to warm the engine block up in cold weather. I found this out by searching my VIN number on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lastvin.com/&quot;&gt;lastvin.com&lt;/a&gt;. This showed part codes for HZ9 HEATER BOOSTER, DIESEL which meant my van had this mini heater installed and more importantly, a fuel line to supply that heater. I had seen other van owners make a T in these auxiliary fuel lines to let both their indoor heater and heater booster access the main tank. I was thrilled to forget about the spare. After inspecting the bottom of the van just in front of the fuel tank I could see the fuel line and the fuel pump that fed the heater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/heater/aux-line.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Auxiliary Fuel Line&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But where to put you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now came the decision of where to locate the heater in the van. By far the most common installation you’ll find is installing the heater facing the rear, beneath the passenger seat. This is a nice spot because your heater air will go directly into the living space behind the passenger seat and you don’t need to cut through much metal to get through the floor of the van. When I went to check out this spot I realized this would not be possible for me. Most passenger seat installs use the 2KW heaters which fit inside the space nicely. I had accidentally purchased the behemouth 8KW heater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/heater/comparison.png&quot; alt=&quot;Auxiliary Fuel Line&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for other options I eventually settled on the drivers side halfway up the van, it was a good spot beneath a seat that the previous owner had put in. It’d be closer to my battery bank and the giant heater would fit inside nicely. First I set about using the template plate that came with the kit to drill the openings for all the “thru-hulls” (great boat lingo for things that go through the floor, a bit scarier in boats). Soon I realied that I was not simply drilling through the metal floor of the van but about an inch of wood flooring above that. This complicated things a bit. The connections between the heater unit and the exhaust intake hoses were crucial and would need to be directly where the pipes left the unit. I figured I’d solve this by pre-attaching the hoses and cutting enough space in the wood flooring to fit the clamps around the bases. This worked surprisingly well and all of a sudden my heater was strapped in tight with two long hoses dangling beneath my van.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Under the van&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing I did was strap the hoses to the side of the van so that they’d be secure. I was careful to make sure the exhaust always sloped down as instructed, supposedly liquid can come down it and if it backs up you’re going to get some things coming out of your heater. Once this was done it was time to setup the fuel line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was certainly the scariest step but I realized it was very simple. I follwed the guidance to install the fuel pump at a slight angle upwards and also so that the line from the pump to the heater was always sloping up so no air bubbles could form. The line from the tank going into the pump could be as crazy as you like. After drilling the pump into position it was time to cut the T in the fuel line. The kit I purchased did not come with a fuel line splitting T so I bought this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09DSPPS7S/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o03_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;fuel line splitter kit&lt;/a&gt; which mentioned the European heaters, thinking it would work for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After fiddling around with the pieces I realized the fuel hose and fuel line I had were not the same size as the auxiliary fuel line running out of my tank. Eventually I found a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lowes.com/pd/EZ-FLO-1-4-in-Inner-Diameter-x-10-ft-Rubber-Fuel-Hose/1000180619&quot;&gt;fuel hose at Lowes&lt;/a&gt; that would work as a buffer between the existing fuel line and the T kit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding the Controller&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The controller that came with my heater was a bit odd but thankfully &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_dAIzvh4IaQ&amp;amp;ab_channel=VanLifeUkACompleteSurvivorsGuide&quot;&gt;this great video&lt;/a&gt; helped me understand its functions and start the priming process. Priming runs the pump without the heater on to fill the fuel line with fuel. Seeing the fuel slowly go through the line was very exciting after all that work without any feedback!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Afterburner Controller&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months after installing the heater and using it frequently I heard of a device called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mrjones.id.au/afterburner/&quot;&gt;The Afterburner&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a super easy to use/understand controller you can use in place of the one shipped with your heater. You need to first make sure your heater is compatible with this controller before you order it, the one purchased and mention above was. With the Afterburner I can turn on my heater by connecting to the Afterburners wifi network on my phone and it has a great display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/heater/afterburner.png&quot; alt=&quot;Afterburner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update after a few months of use..&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This heater has been exactly the thing I was looking for, it works durably and has not caused me any issues thus far. The only downside is the pump does emit a thumping sound that’s audible inside the van. It’s not super bothersome but I could certainly do without it. I imagine if anything happens to this heater I will probably buy another one just like it, the value is superb!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Heating a sprinter van in sub freezing temperatures is difficult, even if it’s insulated. Ideally you want something that is simple, cost-effective, and safe. I did a bit of research and talked to some van folks who suggested using Electric Blankets, Propane Space Heaters, and Diesel Heaters. I ended up trying all three of these options before ditching the rest for the diesel heater (it was by far the best solution).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Denver Prospector Bikepacking Route</title><link href="https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/09/20/the-denver-prospector-bikepacking-route.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Denver Prospector Bikepacking Route" /><published>2022-09-20T18:19:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-09-20T18:19:00-06:00</updated><id>https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/09/20/the-denver-prospector-bikepacking-route</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/09/20/the-denver-prospector-bikepacking-route.html">&lt;p&gt;Colorado has a rich history of adventurers heading from the plains up to the mountains to find fortune. Today most of the folks heading to the mountains are looking to hit the ski slopes or see the aspens turn golden yellow but while the rockies aren’t the wild frontier they used to be, you can still find that same adventure off the highway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously I had done the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bikepacking.com/routes/boulder-bikepacking-loop/&quot;&gt;Boulder Weekend Bikepacking Loop&lt;/a&gt; and really enjoyed the logistic simplicity. No cars to park or shuttle, just a well wrapped weekend of biking and the trail. Surely something similar should exist for Denverites? Sadly it seems we are lagging a bit behind our preppy neighbor to the north. Thus began the Prospector Loop, a weekend-ish length all-road bikepacking route starting and ending in Denver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://ridewithgps.com/embeds?type=route&amp;amp;id=41047827&amp;amp;sampleGraph=true&quot; style=&quot;width: 1px; min-width: 100%; height: 700px; border: none;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ascending-into-summit-county&quot;&gt;Ascending into Summit County&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Route starts at Confluence Park, where Cherry Creek meets the South Platte River. This was the site of the original settlement that would become the city of Denver. Heading West, the route follows rolling hills of bike lanes before joining the Cherry Creak Trail towards the town of Golden. Next comes the Lookout Mountain climb, if you’re making the journey on a weekend you’ll likely be joined by many lycra clad road cyclists who use the climb as a training ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon you’ll be cruising down US Highway 40, which parallels I-70, you may pass some of your Denver pals stuck in traffic! After descending down to Floyd hill, you’ll cross under the Interstate and join the Scott Lancaster Memorial Trail that follows Clear Creak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/prospector/creek-path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Clear Creek Path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed riding so close to Clear Creak, watching the fly fishers and hearing the rush of the rapids. I’d made this journey up I-70 so many times by car and never realized was I was missing. I’d bet on a hot day you’d pass some whitewater rafters coming down the creak yelling with delight!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon you’ll find yourself in Idaho Springs, which has plenty of bathrooms and snack spots to take advantage of. If you’re looking for something filling and have time to spare I’d recommend BBQ at Smokin Yards or Pizza at Beau Jo’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gentle climb continues West towards Dumont, then Georgetown. This is likely the last opportunity to stock up on food and snacks before reaching Summit County so take advantage. Leaving Georgetown, the climbing kicks up a notch and you’ll pass by the Georgetown Loop Railroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few miles past Silver Plume you’ll jump onto a secluded bike path to finish the rest of the journey to the base of Loveland Pass. Climbing up Loveland pass is brutal but the views gained are great and the descent is a thrill!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/prospector/loveland.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Loveland Pass&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Descending Loveland pass is another beautiful view. You can finally rest your legs after climbing for almost a full day. Here is a shot on one of the switch backs descending the south side of Loveland pass just above A-Basin Ski Area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/prospector/loveland-desc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Loveland Pass&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heading down towards Keystone Resort you’ll get off the road and onto the Summit country recreational paths which are all well planned out and maintained. You’ll do a mini climb to get above the Dillon Resovoir and get on your way to Breckenridge, parallelling highway 9 all the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stopping in Breckenridge is nice if you want to stock up on food or buy the gloves you forgot to pack in Denver! If you want to escape the road and people don’t worry, pushing on south of Denver you’ll find great dispersed camping spots along the north side of Boreas Pass road. And did I mention the gravel begins! This is where I met up with a buddy for my first night of camping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/prospector/camp-night.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Camping&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;boreas-pass-and-pike-national-forest&quot;&gt;Boreas Pass and Pike National Forest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking up and boiling some instant coffee. Packing up my bags and saying goodbye to my friend who was heading of to hike for the day. Checking my map I realized heading up to this campsite (a spot called stony point) I had already completed half the climbing of Boreas Pass. This gave me an easy feeling, starting the day with a simple and beautiful climb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boreas Pass used to host a train line that would bring people and goods all the way from Denver up to Breckenridge. Along the road you can see the massive water tower and service station that were once used in operation of the railroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming over Boreas pass in the fall you are sure to see the Aspen leaves changing color to golden yellow. I road this section in late September and met a few bow hunters looking for Elk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cruising down Boreas Pass road towards Como, you’ll see the high plains of Colorado spread out before you. There are plenty of spots on the descent to fill up on water, make sure to do so before you enter the dry plains of South Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/prospector/aspens.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Aspens&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Como has some interesting historical bits to look at if you have the time, mainly an old rail station and a few plaques. Leaving Como you’ll bike on Highway 285 for a brief bit. This is a little unerving as the cars are fast moving but thankfully the shoulder is wide and it’s only a short distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning back to the Southeast on Elkhorn then Albino Road you’ll enjoy wide open views of the highest plains in the country. Heading towards the Tarryall resovoir you’ll transition back onto pavement and make your way to Lake George.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/prospector/plains-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Plains&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lake George has some food support depending on how late you arrive. I stopped at the BBQ shack they had and really liked the brisket sandwhich (not very much a cycling meal but it was delicious).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, It’s time to point Northeast back towards Denver. Out of Lake George, you’ll ride up through a winding mix of gravel and national park roads with plenty of options for camping for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rampart-range-and-chatfield-resovoir&quot;&gt;Rampart Range and Chatfield Resovoir&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heading up through Westcreek you’ll get back on the pavement and head East towards Rampart Range Road, a long gravel section with plenty of camping options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had never seen this part of the state and was in awe of the massive piles of rocks visible from the trail. Make sure to stock up on water for this section as it can get very dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you get to the junction with Jarre Canyon road you have the opportunity to take an easier route down through the paved road to the town of Sedalia, where you can easily rejoin the route at Chatfield resovoir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the Indian Creek Trail ahead has some technical singletrack but is a beautiful end to the foothills section of this route. Continue out through the gravel road that runs through Waterton Canyon and out through to Chatfield Resovoir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here you can follow the Mary Carter Greenway Trail all the way back to Confluence Park! There are plenty of spots to stop along the way for a snack, even a coffee shop along the way called Nixon’s Coffee House!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-gear-for-this-trip&quot;&gt;My Gear for this trip&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bike: Surly Straggler&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Racks: Surly Front Rack and Surly Disk Rear Rack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Packs: Swift Industries Sugarloaf&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sleeping System: Outdoor research Helium Bivvy and 0 Degree Bag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;
.multi-photo {
	width: 100%;
	display: inline-flex;
	justify-content: center;
	flex-wrap: wrap;
}
.photo-box {
	
}
.photo {
	max-height: 400px;
	max-width: 400px;
	padding: 10px;
	object-fit: contain;
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;multi-photo&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/prospector/bivvy.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;/assets/img/prospector/bivvy.jpg&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/prospector/plains.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;/assets/img/prospector/plains.jpg&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/prospector/gtown.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;/assets/img/prospector/gtown.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dan</name></author><summary type="html">Colorado has a rich history of adventurers heading from the plains up to the mountains to find fortune. Today most of the folks heading to the mountains are looking to hit the ski slopes or see the aspens turn golden yellow but while the rockies aren’t the wild frontier they used to be, you can still find that same adventure off the highway.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bikepacking the Pyrenees and Costa Brava</title><link href="https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/08/05/bikepacking-the-pyrenees-and-costa-brava.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bikepacking the Pyrenees and Costa Brava" /><published>2022-08-05T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-08-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/08/05/bikepacking-the-pyrenees-and-costa-brava</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/08/05/bikepacking-the-pyrenees-and-costa-brava.html">&lt;p&gt;Brava Boys 2022&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Bikepacking may ruin future travel for me. The convenience, adventure, and speed allow for a deeper environmental intake’. These words were exchanged over claras on one of our last evenings in Catalunya. They stuck with me as we polished our final days of thrill-seeking riding. I am excited and humbled to share my perspective of an adventure of a lifetime. Thank you Danno for allowing me the space to put pen to paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/brava/image12.png&quot; alt=&quot;bike beach shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I achieved my work sabbatical, I knew I wanted to do something alternative. So many are spent at the beach or exploring the metropolitans of the world. There is nothing wrong with this as we all find refreshment in different experiences, however I knew I wanted something big. The idea of taking on a longer bikepack was something that my mind marinated on for years. I had been inspired by the Lachlan Mortons and Lael Wilcoxs of the world. They could inhale a space at such a more intimate level than what can be experienced by car or even by foot. From the countless hype videos I watched, it seemed as though the adventure never ended. Once the day’s ride was over, the thrill continued in the form of exploring new villages, enjoying foreign foods, or connecting with people from different walks of life. It was inevitable that I would be doing a trip, but where and with who were major question marks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of 2022 I began sending out feelers to a few friends. After much research, I narrowed my gaze to the famous Pyrenees mountains of Spain and France. The rugged mountains paired with the slow beach life of Spain’s Costa Brava seemed like the perfect offset of send and relaxation. In a way to experience as much as possible in limited time, I designed a route that was a point-to-point with neither pole being within Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This presented major logistical challenges, however the additional experiences available offset the extra hurdles. Alright, a loose route was planned, but who to bring? Well I am fortunate to have surrounded myself with incredibly keen and like-minded friends. After some Zoom syncs, text threads, and Strava route building, our roster solidified to the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nate-schneider&quot;&gt;Nate Schneider&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A couple years of bike racing experience, loves riding uphills, chocolate addict, over plans and over packs which don’t mend well with spontaneous bikepacking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/brava/image14.png&quot; alt=&quot;bike beach shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dan-wilson&quot;&gt;Dan Wilson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Charger, dives head first into whatever he sets his mind to, experience with smaller bikepacks, very tall, beautiful mullet, great dancer, diesel engine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/brava/image8.png&quot; alt=&quot;bike beach shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;brian-chorksi&quot;&gt;Brian Chorksi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Day 1 friend from my hometown in Wisconsin, incredibly talented photographer, A1 banter, frustratingly fast for someone who doesn’t have proper cycling training, appreciates taking things slow and enjoying the small experiences of everyday life, stoke is always high&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/brava/image21.png&quot; alt=&quot;bike beach shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this group, we constructed such a fun combination of cycling experience and adventure drive. We were all like-minded, but brought something unique to the table that was leaned on at different times through the adventure. With this in mind, we continued to tweak the route to fit our goals. Lourdes could no longer be our starting city as the trains were fully booked out. Tourmalet could not be climbed as the time investment to get to the base was too much of a sacrifice. Through all the challenges, we adapted and came up with something special. Unbeknownst to us, these initial adaptations and challenges were foreshadowing of what was to come. Enough of the background, let’s get into the adventure. I chose abbreviated bullet lists as my 6 hour layover isn’t a long enough time for me to highlight everything that happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;logistical-hurdles&quot;&gt;Logistical Hurdles:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course our adventure began with logistical challenges. Despite all the hard work we did ahead of time, not everything can be forecasted. Danno and I made some last minute pivots to store our luggage at a hostel across town. After a daunting expedition across Barca with fully loaded bikes, empty bike bags, backpacks and duffle bags, we were off to a bus station to take us to La Seu d’Urgell. We attempted to board the bus, however the driver gauffed at us and would not allow us to board with unbagged bikes. I gave us a 2% chance of boarding and had already committed to finding a train, blabla car or car rental when Danno came sprinting down the track with 3 bike ‘drapes’. We had 2 minutes to get them packed to the driver’s liking. He towered over us and tapped his watch as we scrambled. We threw the bikes under the bus, unsecured to anything, protected by the thinnest microfiber material available. The ‘bag’ was a formality but served no protective purpose. This buzzer beater effort by Danno got us on the bus and headed to the start line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Route snafoozs are bound to happen with a route this big, but overall things went pretty smoothly. We had a route malfunction at the base of Port du Bales (causing a hike-a-bike up a 30% grade), then some gravel that required some walking around Costa Brava. The last challenge was during our push from Cadaques to Begur. We were supposed to ride through a national park that was randomly closed due to wildfire concerns. We debated ducking the rope for the couple miles of riding we had planned. Fortunately, we elected not to and as we were turning around, some park rangers pulled up. We had to navigate our way around the city via Google Maps which still led us to multiple gravel sections, however we avoided a fine or worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all had fun journeys to and from Barcelona. Unfortunately mine is still ongoing at the moment, but hoping it is uneventful as this morning provided enough challenges to last me awhile. UPDATE - Made it home safely and on time, however BCN airport threw everything it could at me, including: waiting in wrong ticket line for 1.5 hours, needing run across the airport atrium twice to drop off my bike, finally checking in but being notified I’d be flying standby, needing to go through security twice, having to navigate a passport check that had 2 separate queues, being brought into a fogged-windowed room and asked questions while a thorough search of my bags was completed….again, finally receiving a boarding pass / seat assignment but being stopped on the bridge by another agent who asked to do a 3rd thorough search of my bags (my stamped boarding pass allowed me to proceed without interference).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;misfortunes&quot;&gt;Misfortunes:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Stage 1, Chorski suffered a flat tire on his tubeless setup. We were about 5 miles from our destination of Valencia d’Aneu when we spotted a cute mountain village where we wanted to stop. When trying to snag a photo of us riding the narrow streets, he rolled over a sewer drain that was just enough to create a side puncture on the edge of the rim. Our many prayers to the sealant gods were answered, at least enough to get him the next 5 miles, but we needed professional help. After 3 trips and multiple attempts from a local bike shop, a new tire and tube had us rolling again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chorski wasn’t the only one to suffer a mechanical. Danno rolled over something sharp as we pulled into Argeles Su Mer (a bustling tourist trap that felt like a crappy Floridian city (no offense)). The quietness of the mountain villages was immediately replaced by children screaming, spring break-esque kids blaring music, and trashy boardwalk / flea markets trying to sell you funnel cakes and graphic tshirts. It was the worst time to get a flat not because we were in a pickle, but we were truly taken back as our previous 7 days had felt so incredibly different. Kudos to Danno though because his bacon strip maneuver had us up and running just a handful of minutes later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our last day in Girona, we met some Catalan women on top of the Rocacorba climb. This was a challenging, curvy climb where the world’s best would flock to complete their annual fitness tests. On the descent, one of the women went down and landed some gnarly road rash. She was able to roll back to Girona after a cafe stop and some first-aid work. An unfortunate event for her (luckily she was tough), however it allowed us more time to chat with them which led to a very fun final night in Spain. Oh yeah, the bike was ok too (for the cyclists out there wondering about its status).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;
.multi-photo {
	width: 100%;
	display: inline-flex;
	justify-content: center;
	flex-wrap: wrap;
}
.photo-box {
	
}
.photo {
	max-height: 400px;
	max-width: 400px;
	padding: 10px;
	object-fit: contain;
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;multi-photo&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/brava/image25.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;/assets/img/brava/image25.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/brava/image13.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;/assets/img/brava/image13.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/brava/image26.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;/assets/img/brava/image26.png&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;riding-highlights&quot;&gt;Riding Highlights:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a lover of anything uphill, I adored our Hors Categorie climbs (aka really stinkin hard climbs). We summited the following mighty climbs: Port de la Bonaigua, Col du Portillon, Port du Bales, Col de Mente, Col de Portet d’Aspet, Port de Lers, Goulier Neige, many unclassified highway climbs and tons of steep kickers along the Costa Brava. All presented different challenges based on how the legs felt, where they fell during the day, and other environmental factors. Climbing hits different when you are slugging around an extra 30 pounds of gear. 
The diversity of the riding was truly incredible. Each day we were treated to different ecosystems, weather conditions and vistas. Some days we’d start in a scorching hot mountain town then climb up well above tree level and descend through the thickest fog imaginable. Other days we’d wake up and cruise the rolly hills of the coast while making consistent stops for papas bravas. Some days were heads down as we viewed them as transition stages. Others we stopped at every opportunity to fully breathe in the moment. We’d pass seaside villas, mountain top castles and fairytale villages that each had stunning churches and drinkable water springs that saved our butts many times. It’s truly hard to describe all the incredible views we were treated to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, just the overall accessibility via bikes is unmatched. We never hesitated when wanting to go check something out. Whether it was a trip to a neighboring town, the beach for a quick dip, or just running across town for food, the bikes always provided us a means of transportation with 0 wait time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;
.multi-photo {
	width: 100%;
	display: inline-flex;
	justify-content: center;
	flex-wrap: wrap;
}
.photo-box {
	
}
.photo {
	max-height: 400px;
	max-width: 400px;
	padding: 10px;
	object-fit: contain;
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;multi-photo&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/brava/image34.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;/assets/img/brava/image34.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image17.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image17.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image10.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image10.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image22.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image22.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image11.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image11.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image32.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image32.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image27.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image27.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image18.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image18.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image1.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image1.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image3.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image3.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image2.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image2.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image31.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image31.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image33.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image33.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image20.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image20.png&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;food&quot;&gt;Food:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite things we did was mid-ride grocery heists. Chorski may be the goat of adventure grocery shopping. We’d send him in with some requests and he’d return with a delicious shmorgishborg of healthy food. He ensured we had fruits and veggies as so many of our other meals consisted of bread, cheese and some form of ham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some foods were daily deletions for the guys. Everyday we’d eat multiple croissants (usually with chocolate), espressos, prosciutto sandwiches and claras (a ½ beer, ½ lemon fanta mix). This carb bomb was incredibly convenient and kept our engines running, but the diversity of our fancier dinners made them taste that much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most foreign thing to me was their mountain top refugees. We’d climb the mighty Port du Bales, a 10 mile climb of unforgiving grade, only to find a cute summit cafe serving up charcuterie boards, crepes, wine, espressos and baked goods in the parking lot. We finished the killer Col de Menthe which zapped the life out of all of us, only to find a small cafe at the summit with beers and cheap crepes. These were life savers and made the harder days that much more enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, you can’t hit Costa Brava / Catalunya without some incredible seafood. We splurged on octopus, calamari, ceviches, tartars, different fish filets and mussels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;
.multi-photo {
	width: 100%;
	display: inline-flex;
	justify-content: center;
	flex-wrap: wrap;
}
.photo-box {
	
}
.photo {
	max-height: 400px;
	max-width: 400px;
	padding: 10px;
	object-fit: contain;
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;multi-photo&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/brava/image30.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;/assets/img/brava/image30.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image15.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image15.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image19.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image19.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image6.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image6.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image29.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image29.png&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;extras&quot;&gt;Extras:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first rest day happened in Bagneres du Luchon, a small town just on the French side of the border. It was surrounded by massive mountains and ski resorts. The neighboring Pseyroudes played host to a Tour de France stage that we attempted to attend via hitchhiking, however no one wanted to pick up 3 raggedy looking Americans, shocking right? Since we missed out on the Tour, we took the extra energy into our rest day and rode to the base of a hike to Lac d’Oo. We hammered the steep hike and were rewarded with Pandora-esque views of an alpine lake surrounded by steep walls and waterfalls. Without hesitation, the boys jumped in and began swimming in its ‘refreshing’ water. Again, it’s hard to describe its beauty without some photographic support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The running joke of ‘Are the boys going out tonight?’ seemed like it’d result in an utter flop, however a spontaneous final night in Girona led us to a discoteca. The Girona girls and their Argentinian flatmate played tour guides and took us to a local: restaurant for a traditional jagermeister-like drink and long-distance wine drinking, tavern for foosball and darts, then a discoteca for some dancing. We ended up getting pretty toasty and I’m pretty sure my shoes are still cooling off from tearing up the dance floor (at least I thought I did in my drunken stuber). It was an awesome time and something I was hoping to experience at least once on the trip. We finished the night with a 4am run through town as a way to speed up our arrival to the bnb as our 8am alarm was looming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;
.multi-photo {
	width: 100%;
	display: inline-flex;
	justify-content: center;
	flex-wrap: wrap;
}
.photo-box {
	
}
.photo {
	max-height: 400px;
	max-width: 400px;
	padding: 10px;
	object-fit: contain;
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;multi-photo&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/brava/image28.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;/assets/img/brava/image28.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image24.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image24.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image5.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image5.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image7.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image7.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image23.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image23.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image4.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image4.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image16.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image16.png&quot; /&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image9.png&quot; class=&quot;photo previewable&quot; alt=&quot;
		/assets/img/brava/image9.png&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lodging-issues&quot;&gt;Lodging Issues:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was truly incredible at how many weird lodging things happened to us. It almost seemed as if every place was great, however we’d just be waiting for the ‘but…’ that always presented itself. From multiple places not having wifi or power, to having to schedule check-ins / walkouts without wifi, to needing to rent bedsheets, to actually being physically locked out of our bnb for 6 hours and ‘forced’ to go hang at the beach, to being accused of losing bnb keys…. twice, neither of which actually happened. We always found solutions to make things work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I just wanted to touch on a few of my favorite moments from the trip. Ones that will never leave me, no matter how big or small:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;During our first climb on stage 1, we ran into a bike tour with riders from Miami. We rode with them momentarily, leapfrogging each other as we continued our way up and down the mountains. Then stopping at the tiniest bar imaginable that had some epic views off its back patio. The most athletic moment of the entire trip may have been seeing Chorski get in an incredibly low sumo squat to take some photos of his drinks on that back patio.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Climbing a ribbon of switchbacks on Port de la Bonaigua which led us to a ski resort summit where we were treated to incredible vistas of raw peaks and cows dotting the mountainside. We briefly stopped to take in the summit views as well as some calories. As we crested, we realized we’d be descending through layers of moody clouds until we hit the valley floor. The energy became absolutely electric. Yips of excitement bounced off the mountain walls as we plunged and disappeared into the clouds below.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The multi-cafe stop at Lac d’Oo where Chorski was just chopping it up with our server. We hit pre and post hike food. The rest-day wasn’t so restful, but the alpine lake was unforgettable.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Somehow always finding hilltop hotels at La Solayan and Goulier where we’d have to make one final ascent after already being put to shambles.
During our climb of Port de Lers, we met a woman from Rice Lake, WI who had moved to Santiago Chile. We hung out at a paragliding launch spot and watched her partner run off the edge of a mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Having a truly eventful evening / morning in Quillon which we expected to be a quiet time. This included swimming at a local water hole, having a ‘lack of dinner’ scare with a Vietnamese restaurant being super slow and thinking no other food was available in town (ended up getting their appetizers and a pizza), then having an incredible breakfast cooked for us the next morning.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Exploring Cadaques: snapping photos of it’s incredible beauty, swimming in the Mediterranean, eating at Celeste and jamming out to some locals playing on some alley.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hitting the incredible beaches that surrounded Begur. We visited multiple places where we swam, did some minor cliff diving, juggled some footy, watched locals throw backflips and drank diy claras. Chorski’s stoke really showed here.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Exploring Girona’s old town and really soaking up their crazy bike culture. We hit multiple bike cafes in La Fabrica and Hors Categorie. Then the crazy night that ensued where we really let ourselves go for the first time. Danno really tore up the dancefloor and his sunglasses were a hit at the discoteca.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Just all the fun cafe, restaurant runs where we just had great conversations. Sometimes we’d get deep and talk about relationships, career goals and dreams. Sometimes we just talked about soccer or about how tired we were. All were cherishable moments.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The many people we met along the way. Hard to highlight all, but here are some memorable ones: bike tour from Miami, awesome waitress in Valencia d’Aneu + hotel owner, bikepackers met at summit heading to Bagneres du Luchon, bikepacking duo of father/son from Germany, waiter at Lac d’Oo who hooked us up, Rice Lake woman and a saxaphone player who had a gig that night, hotel owner up Goulier, our bnb host at Quillon who was so sweet, Dutch rider on our push to Begur, dinner with the Creative Director from Black Sheep and his awesome ex-pro turned Black Sheep savant wife, and the Girona girls who played tour guides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the sake of brevity and not being too much of a time commitment, I am going to wrap up this lengthy report. Many thanks to everyone who made this such a memorable experience. Special thanks to Danno and Chorski as these memories will last a lifetime. I have a feeling this is just V1 for the Brava Boys. Excited for whatever is next. The boys got on a sick one.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nate</name></author><summary type="html">Brava Boys 2022</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Summer Skiing the Bloody Couloir in Mammoth CA</title><link href="https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/06/20/summer-skiing-the-bloody-couloir-in-mammoth-ca.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summer Skiing the Bloody Couloir in Mammoth CA" /><published>2022-06-20T07:38:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-06-20T07:38:00-06:00</updated><id>https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/06/20/summer-skiing-the-bloody-couloir-in-mammoth-ca</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/06/20/summer-skiing-the-bloody-couloir-in-mammoth-ca.html">&lt;p&gt;I had made it a 2022 goal to ski 3 of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.50classicskidescents.com/&quot;&gt;Classic North American Ski Descents&lt;/a&gt; and the ski season was rapidly coming to a close. After turning away from the summit of Mt Hood earlier I still needed that third descent. I was making my way down from San Francisco to Los Angeles and had seen one of the famous lines was located “sort-of” along the way near Mammoth Lakes, CA. After consulting my Sierra Ski Book and a few ski blogs &lt;a href=&quot;https://snowbrains.com/trip-report-bloody-mountain-ca-bloody-couloir/&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sierradescents.com/skiing/bloody/bloody-couloir.html#:~:text=Bloody%20Couloir%20is%20usually%20the,and%20a%20more%20moderate%20angle.&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; I figured I’d give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bloody Couloir is one of the most accessible of the classic descents (Probably aside from the Silver Couloir) &lt;em&gt;IF&lt;/em&gt; you have a very rugged vehicle to get up the road. I soon realized that while I thought I had an “adventure car” my 2008 Honda Pilot was no match for this terrain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/bloody/IMG_1661.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Laurel Lakes Road is Treacherous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I set out on foot and headed up the road eager to get a better glimpse at the couloir in the morning sun. The mind games are always at play on an early approach hike like this especially when you’re solo. “Do I really need to be here?” “Is this even skiable?”, for me personally there’s a moment where I really commit to a trip and it doesn’t usually happen until I’m about 25% in. Fighting these mind games is a necessary and sort of carthartic experience for me and I think the best skill a person can have in the mountains is the ability to separate irrational fear from legitimate risk. Eventually after pushing through my “agony in the garden” moment I arrived at the base of the couloir and knew that the third descent was in the bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/bloody/IMG_1688.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The line is in!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The snow was covered with a layer of sand but the snow was firm near the bottom as I started up the apron. The biggest issue on my mind was the time, it was mid morning and I knew I needed to hurry to get above potential rock fall areas. The approach hike had taken two hours and I promised myself I’d get a lift kit installed before next time. I hugged the lookers left side of the couloir and climbed into the lower opening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/bloody/IMG_1692.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Climbing into the bottleneck&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mountain is named “Bloody Mountain” because the rocks are a deep red color like blood. I remember reading about this but it was very cool to see in person. It gave the area a distinct character and contrast. I had turned of my music to be hyper aware of any movement above me and could occasionally hear little bits of sand shifting. The rushing waterfall near the base of the couloir told me a lot was going on underneath the hard snow surface I was hiking on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I reached the upper rock tower and had to decide which way to go around it. Lookers right offered a steeper pitch but a more straight shot up to the ridge. Lookers left seemed to require a few lateral moves to get around rock ledges where the snow had melted away. Opting for efficiency, I very carefully had a snack then proceeded up the right pitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I got to where the snow ended, it looked to be about 10 more feet through loose rock to the ridge. I was happy just to start the ski down and skip the ridge as I didn’t feel too comfortable scrambling up steep loose rock with my skis packed up. The snow near the top was very slushy and this worried me as I punched through in my crampons. I knew the route I had just come up was not skiable and would need to navigate the narrow snow paths on skiers right to descend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/bloody/IMG_1703.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tricky Descent&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t want to get to the opening to the line on my skis and realize it wasn’t didn’t go so I downclimbed to the rock ridge to get a better view and could see a nice route all the way down to the apron. It would be tight skiing at the top but the once past the top choke point the line got wider and wider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/bloody/IMG_1707.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Staring at the route&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously I had been a little spooked in my crampons, I felt top heavy and was punching deep into the snow while downclimbing. As soon as my skis were on I felt much more comfortable on the slope. I took care and the first few turns, making sure to be balanced and feeling ever inch of the ski. Soon I was below the rock towers and in the wide chute heading towards the bottom. The snow was soft but very choppy, making it difficult to string together more than a few turns. Looking back I could see my skis were carving a white line through the sandy snow, like I was wiping my finger through a dusty windshield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the top of the apron I was able to do a bit more aggressive skiing, finding softer continuous snow. I was thrilled to be out of the rock fall zone and skiing a classic in June. When I reached the bottom my feet were grateful to get back into my wide running shoes and I turned to look back at my line down the Bloody Couloir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/bloody/IMG_1714.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;White line in the sandy snow&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to come back and do this line again when it can be skied from the ridge but I was glad I had knocked out my 3rd classic and happy crushed the 2hr walk back to the car in solitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;strava-embed-placeholder&quot; data-embed-type=&quot;activity&quot; data-embed-id=&quot;7267033335&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://strava-embeds.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>dan</name></author><summary type="html">I had made it a 2022 goal to ski 3 of the Classic North American Ski Descents and the ski season was rapidly coming to a close. After turning away from the summit of Mt Hood earlier I still needed that third descent. I was making my way down from San Francisco to Los Angeles and had seen one of the famous lines was located “sort-of” along the way near Mammoth Lakes, CA. After consulting my Sierra Ski Book and a few ski blogs 1 and 2 I figured I’d give it a go.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://daniellytle.github.io/assets/img/bloody/IMG_1688.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://daniellytle.github.io/assets/img/bloody/IMG_1688.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hammering Mount Shasta Through Avalanche Gulch</title><link href="https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/06/04/hammering-mount-shasta-through-avalanche-gulch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hammering Mount Shasta Through Avalanche Gulch" /><published>2022-06-04T21:41:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-06-04T21:41:00-06:00</updated><id>https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/06/04/hammering-mount-shasta-through-avalanche-gulch</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/06/04/hammering-mount-shasta-through-avalanche-gulch.html">&lt;p&gt;In 2017 I flew from Michigan to California to climb Mt. Shasta with my friend Matt. The plan was to camp at altitude to accelerate the aclimation process and do a summit push the next day. It was an ill fated expedition for myself as I woke up on summit day with a splitting headache and was sick at 9,000 ft. While I was happy to be back at the car after shuffling down the mountain at 5am, it’s weighed on me for a while now. After building some mountaineering skills and fitness over the last few years I figured it was time to take another crack at one of Californias few 14ers and this time bring my skis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After doing the Haute Route, and reading about a guy who did a Mt Hood speed run in minimal clothing/gear I was sold on the fast and light technique. This meant forgoing the acclimation day and doing a 1 day summit push. This meant 7,000ft elevation gain but much less gear and fussing with said gear. I had done a gravel bike race 2 days prior in the area around Mt. Shasta, I figured that would count for a bit of acclimation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/shasta/IMG_1559.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Recon Hike&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured a recon hike the day before would give me a good idea of the conditions and spot where I would transition to my ski boots. Mt. Shasta has a few glaciers on it but the Avalanche Gulch Route which approaches the mountain from the South has none. After hiking up about 2 miles and chatting with a few other skiers coming down after their summit I felt pretty good about the conditions and settled in for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/shasta/IMG_1565.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wake Up Call&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my alarm went off at 2am I was really not in the mood. My twin air mattress felt like a Temperpedic and I layed there for a bit. Eventually I found the motivation to get moving and brave the brisk air outside. It was Monday morning and there wasn’t much activity at the trailhead. I set off alone up the trail and was feeling good. I had some tunes going and was in my soft running shoes making good time towards the ski boot transition point. I passed the Horse Camp hut and from this point could see a few headlamps high up on the mountain. These were people who had camped at the high altitude Lake Helen the night before and were pushing for the summit early in hopes of watching the sunrise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached the snow and began the skinning on the hard bumpy snow. I had figured this snow would grip like the Mt Hood skinning I had done recently and had chosen to leave my Ski Crampons at the car, as the slope pitched up I was slipping and sliding every other step. Cursing myself for not bringing this special tool that was exactly the thing I needed now, I was getting a bit worried about how the other 5-6k feet would go. Eventually the sloped pitched back down as I headed up towards Helen Lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just above Helen Lake I looked back to see the sun hit the valley below me and could just make out the headlamp of one climber heading up far behind me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pitch of the slope above Helen Lake quickly increased to an angle that would require boot crampons. While I stopped to transition and have a bite to eat the hiker below me caught up and I got to chat with him for a brief time. We would end up playing tag the rest of the ascent to the lower ridge, from there we would hike to the summit together. It was nice to have a companion for conversation and safety as well, these fleeting mountain friendships are special but usually over very soon, especially since he was purely on foot and I would be skiing down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming above the ridge I would meet a few climbers glissading down from the summit including the folks that witnessed the sunrise from the top. It was still early morning and the sliding must’ve been quite rough. We came up to “Misery Hill” and found a nearly dry proper switchback trail, the first of the entire climb (mostly the avalanche gulch hike is taken straight at the lower ridge). After Misery Hill we were a bit confused and consulted our maps as a few peaks are visible and it’s not clearly visible which is the true summit. Eventually we found our way North, passing near a gas vent close to the summit. The smell was very noticable and I began to think the encroaching headache was more due to sulfur inhalation than lack of oxygen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/shasta/IMG_1571.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alpine Gas Vent&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon we hooked around up the final ridge to the summit and enjoyed hazy mid morning views in every direction around northern California. Mt Shasta is incredible in it’s isolation from other large peaks and it felt like we were in a hot air balloon at 14,180 feet in the sky. It was 9:30am, I was pretty happy with my timing and wouldn’t have to worry about hurrying down the mountain. It was very windy at the summit and I didn’t like the way my skis on my back would catch the wind so my buddy and I exchanged summit pictures and parted ways to descend the mountain. He had a long way to climb/slide back to the trailhead and I had an exciting much anticipated ski line to choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/shasta/IMG_4929.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;At the summit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-ski-descent&quot;&gt;The Ski Descent&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the summit down to the lower ridge the conditions were rough. “Bulletproof” is a ski term I would ascribe to those high altitude conditions and I chattered my way down through the lower ridge chutes, grateful to be moving so quickly. Eventually I found my way West to smooth open slopes that had caught the sun earlier in the day. My quads certainly did not have the juice to do 6k of skiing continuously so I would find small rock patches to wait beneath to catch my breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/shasta/IMG_1587.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Heading down&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I had descended to the sweet spot altitude where the snow was soft and slushy and began to transition from safe skiing to party mode, much to the chagrin of the late morning hikers heading up the gulch. After cruising through maybe 2k of slush I was back at the end of the snow field where I had been at 5am that morning. My feet were grateful to be out of the ski boots and into my wide running shoes. Soon I was bounding down the trail towards the trailhead and a hearty lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;strava-activity&quot;&gt;Strava Activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;strava-embed-placeholder&quot; data-embed-type=&quot;activity&quot; data-embed-id=&quot;7191564579&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://strava-embeds.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>dan</name></author><summary type="html">In 2017 I flew from Michigan to California to climb Mt. Shasta with my friend Matt. The plan was to camp at altitude to accelerate the aclimation process and do a summit push the next day. It was an ill fated expedition for myself as I woke up on summit day with a splitting headache and was sick at 9,000 ft. While I was happy to be back at the car after shuffling down the mountain at 5am, it’s weighed on me for a while now. After building some mountaineering skills and fitness over the last few years I figured it was time to take another crack at one of Californias few 14ers and this time bring my skis.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://daniellytle.github.io/assets/img/shasta/IMG_1587.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://daniellytle.github.io/assets/img/shasta/IMG_1587.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Trip Report: Bikepacking 101, My First Overnight Tour</title><link href="https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/05/09/trip-report-bikepacking-101-my-first-overnight-bike-tour.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trip Report: Bikepacking 101, My First Overnight Tour" /><published>2022-05-09T16:19:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-05-09T16:19:00-06:00</updated><id>https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/05/09/trip-report-bikepacking-101-my-first-overnight-bike-tour</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/05/09/trip-report-bikepacking-101-my-first-overnight-bike-tour.html">&lt;p&gt;Something I’ve always liked about biking is how far you can go and by extension, how much you can see. It makes sense that the hot new activity these days is “bikepacking”, or carrying gear to do multi-day trips on bikes. My cousin Sarah Swallow (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/sarahjswallow/?hl=en&quot;&gt;@sarahjswallow&lt;/a&gt;) has been in the bikepacking world for years and has traveled the globe planning routes and even bootstraping entire bikepacking events. She inspired me to take a crack at it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plan was to get the necessary gear, do a bit of a trial run with it, then take off! I checked around on &lt;a href=&quot;bikepacking.com&quot;&gt;bikepacking.com&lt;/a&gt; for a route close by and found &lt;a href=&quot;https://bikepacking.com/routes/boulder-bikepacking-loop/&quot;&gt;The Boulder Bikepacking Weekender&lt;/a&gt;. I figured I could do it “From the door” as my buddy says, and head from my house in Denver 30 miles to the start of the route in Boulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;testing-out-the-gear&quot;&gt;Testing out the gear&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s totally worth doing test runs in new gear before you get deep into a spot where there’s no cell service, or shops, or cover. It’s never fun to do but I’ve been burned enough times that I know the worth of knowing what to expect from my gear. The biggest question mark in my mind for this trip was my sleep system. Would it be warm enough? Would it pack light enough? I had to do a test run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/bivvy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Backyard Bivvy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite nonstop train horns and street racing noise I managed to sleep relatively comfortably! I was very excited about the bivvy bag as it was so much lighter and smaller than a full tent. I felt happy with my setup and ready to try it out in the field. A few days later I packed up the rig and set off for boulder where I would begin climbing into the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/leaving-the-house.png&quot; alt=&quot;Leaving the house&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving the house, the bike didn’t feel very heavy. Eventually I would feel ever single kilo of it on a very climbing intensive route. All in all it was a somewhat light setup. Still fretting over a heavier-than-needed pack used in my Haute Route tour, I opted for only what I would absolutely need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After making the relaxed journey from Denver to Boulder which is about 30 miles on mostly bike path, I met up with my pal Peter who had agreed to ride with me up the first bits of the route. In Boulder, We stopped at Boxcar Coffee which clearly was one of the popular cyclist hangouts as the bike to person ratio seemed close to one. After watching the Sunday group rides take off we hopped on our bikes and headed west into the Canyon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-first-climb&quot;&gt;The First Climb&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heading West up Boulder canyon, the route then climbs up to the south to meetup with Flagstaff Road and then continues on the highway to another gravel road on the way to Nederland. I figured I would see where I was in the afternoon and make a call about where to camp. Peter was on high mountain bike, casually spinning up the steep incline while I ground hard in my lowest gear. It was then I realized, “I think this gearing might be a problem”. In bicycle climbing vernacular, there are two ways to do it, “Spinning” - pedaling quickly while in a very low gear, and “Grinding” - pedaling somewhat slowly in a higher gear (sometimes standing up out of the saddle). Usually it’s refreshing to do a bit of both, this gives different muscles a chance to tap in and out. I had thought my gearing was relatively well set up for climbing, but it was certainly no mountain bike gearing. For the rest of the trip I would have to do 10%-13% grade climbs at a very low RPM, gripping the handlebar to keep my leg pressing muscles seated on the bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After chatting with Peter a bit more about the route, I had decided to make some detours to avoid a busy highway in favor of more secluded gravel. Changing the route as you ride it is always a fun gamble. As always, I was fighting with my Garmin bike computer, and it did not like me trying to make changes while it was recording my activity. Peter said farewell where the route met Flagstaff road and immediately following his departure the going got tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/singletrack.png&quot; alt=&quot;Singletrack Trail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went from pushing my bike up steep grade roads to cursing while riding mountain bike single track. Each large stone I failed to dodge would catapult my rear into a standing position, as if the ground was yelling at me to get up and peddle harder. At one point I passed two dirtbikers whose presence should have alerted me to the condition of the road to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/trail-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Gnarly Trail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I was saved by a smooth gravel road which led me almost directly to Nederland and a pizza shop. After scarffing two slices and about a gallon of pepsi, I set off on the leg connecting Nederland to Ward (another funky Colorado mountain town loved by cyclists). Heading up to the West on Caribou road made me feel the weight of the bike. This steep dirt road steadily climbed and climbed until I could see snow drifts all around. After reaching the junction where I was too turn North it became clear that I would need to find an alternate route. Road 505 which headed north towards ward was full of snow and looked impassible (I was kicking myself as the seasonal conditions of this road were mentioned in the route report). After chatting with some late afternoon skiers getting ready to hit the slopes nearby I headed back down into Nederland to take the highway shoulder to Ward. It was getting late in the day and I knew I likely wouldn’t make it before dark. In Nederland I found Gordan Gulch campground close by and set off hoping to get there with plenty of daylight left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-first-night&quot;&gt;The First Night&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pulling into Gordan Gulch was a relief and I was excited to set up all my new equipment in the field. After setting out my bivvy and sleeping bag I started to boil up some water for dinner to realize I had forgotten my utensils! I was still hungry enough to chow down the mountain house beef stroganoff in any way I could think off. I ended up using the preservative packet inside that says “DO NOT EAT THIS” as a spoon. After packing up my food supplies I followed bear protocol by hanging my portable kitchen up over a tree branch. It felt like a bit of a hassle but I’m sure with time it’ll feel like second nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/camp.png&quot; alt=&quot;Camp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/camp-food.png&quot; alt=&quot;Camp Food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally I sleep on my side, which I’ve found difficult to accomplish in past camping experiences. Ultralight bikepacking certainly didn’t allow any luxuries that would make that possible. Once it got pretty dark I tucked in on my back and arranged the bug net so I could see the stars and breath fresh air. Some day I’ll be so tired that my body will give up and learn to conk out purely on my back Sleeping Beauty style but this was not that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was glad when the sun rose as it meant I could stop pretending to sleep and get moving again. The temperature had gotten below what I expected and I shivered in the 38 degree morning air. Packing up camp warmed me up in no time, I skipped the luxury of morning coffee as I didn’t feel the need but I can imagine on a longer trip it would be enough to continually get me out of bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting off my devices were charged and I was heading for home! I knew a long day awaited me but I was excited about the journey and my bed awaiting me in Denver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-two&quot;&gt;Day Two&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pulled into Ward, CO soon after departing and the town was still asleep. I’d heard it was a cyclists destination and could tell this was true by the big “Scratch Energy” banner on the side of the General Store, making it clear to cyclists “this is where you can buy your special candy”. I encountered some funky weather coming out of the West but even with a bit of hail the sun shining in the East kept me warm and positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/ward.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ward&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/ward-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ward 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pulled off the road to start a big gravel ascent up towards Gold Hill, another popular Boulder cyclist spot. I was again cursing my gear ratio as I grinded up 10-13% grades. Some might say an 800ft climb is the best way to jump start the legs and at the top I was happy and stoked to be sitting on top of a ton of elevation, ready to coast down to some luxuries in town. Little did I know the route still had one last surprise in store for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-switzerland-trail&quot;&gt;The Switzerland Trail&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d seen postcards that described Colorado as the “Switzerland” of the US. This is brilliant marketing and got me pumped to ride The Switzerland Trail, a 5-6 mile section of gravel heading down towards Boulder. Soon I was wishing I had brought a dirt bike. Smooth gravel bits were intersperced with large loose rocks and the kinds of stones that look baked into the dirt. I cursed and bounced along for nearly the whole trail then finished with a slower slow climb to a trailhead. Popping out into a parking lot full of ATVs and Jeeps getting ready to take on the Switzerland trail made me feel badass but I honestly would not go back there on anything less than a hardtail mountain bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/road.png&quot; alt=&quot;Switzerland Trail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I was back on smooth gravel then onto pavement. Now the huge burden from my heavy bike lay on my disc brakes and I hurtled down towards Boulder. My front brake would positively sing when I pulled it hard but I was too tired to care about that anymore and I stayed on the brakes as my bike sung out for Boulder canyon to hear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rolling-back-to-denver&quot;&gt;Rolling back to Denver&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Coke and a sandwich in Boulder was a massive pick me up and soon I was ready to head out onto the plains. The sun was shining bright and I knew this would be a toasty final 30 miles. The Route from Denver to Boulder is pretty good, the US-30 bikeway provides secluded paved path for most of it. I was happily rolling along until getting to the most gnarly section, a spot just north of Denver that requires a good amount of sidewalk / side-highway riding. I always underestimate how much I enjoy the seclusion of gravel roads and riding next to snarling F-350s made me fondly remember even the worst parts of the Switzerland Trail. Someday I’ll find a better route through that industrial northern Denver neighborhood. Pulling back onto the Cherry creek trail felt great and I savored the last few miles to home through Wash Park and eventually back to the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/denver.png&quot; alt=&quot;Denver in the distance!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do as much as you can to know the route. I love figuring stuff out on the fly and being surprised by the beauty of things but I wished I would’ve brought a bit of a softer bike with lower gearing. If I’m being honest the best way for me to learn this lesson was to go on this trip. Plan 30% of things I’d like to say :).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dan</name></author><category term="trip-report" /><category term="bikepacking" /><summary type="html">Something I’ve always liked about biking is how far you can go and by extension, how much you can see. It makes sense that the hot new activity these days is “bikepacking”, or carrying gear to do multi-day trips on bikes. My cousin Sarah Swallow (@sarahjswallow) has been in the bikepacking world for years and has traveled the globe planning routes and even bootstraping entire bikepacking events. She inspired me to take a crack at it!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://daniellytle.github.io/assets/img/boulder-weekend/valley.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://daniellytle.github.io/assets/img/boulder-weekend/valley.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Trip Report: Spring Skiing the Silver Couloir</title><link href="https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/05/06/trip-report-spring-skiing-the-silver-couloir.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trip Report: Spring Skiing the Silver Couloir" /><published>2022-05-06T15:39:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-05-06T15:39:00-06:00</updated><id>https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/05/06/trip-report-spring-skiing-the-silver-couloir</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/05/06/trip-report-spring-skiing-the-silver-couloir.html">&lt;p&gt;The Silver Couloir is a popular ski line of the north east side of Buffalo Mountain in Summit County, CO. Famous for being included in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.50classicskidescents.com/&quot;&gt;50 Classic Ski Descents in North America&lt;/a&gt;, it offers skiers a chance to link themselves to the famous book with just a quick tour from the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/silver/silver-gpx.png&quot; alt=&quot;Silver Couloir Route&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last Saturday in April had offered perfect weather: bluebird skies and warm temperatures. Knowing this we had planned to get to the summit early before the snow warmed too much. Just when we were about to set off up the trail I realized I had forgotten my avy beacon back in Denver. I had carpooled with my friend Zach who agreed to wait until one of the sports shops in summit county opened and I could grab a beacon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 8:30am we were back at the trailhead and transmitting strong beacon signals. The skintrack wasted no time getting up the east side of buffalo mountain and soon we were skinning up steep switchbacks nearing the treeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/silver/treeline.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Treeline&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about an hour of ascent we had reached treeline and were out on the east face of Buffalo Mountain. The view of Summit County was incredible and we could see the ski runs of Keystone and the soaring peaks of Grays and Torreys across the valley. We had plenty of company as it was the perfect weekend to ski the Silver Couloir. We met splitboarders, a guy in alpine boots, and a couple on their third date (All normal for a Colorado classic).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/silver/open.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Open&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the skinning leveled off we cruised all the way to the summit, unknowingly we had cruised right past the entrance to the couloir. It was nice to hang for a bit at the summit, get a bite to eat, then have a short warm up ski before dropping into the couloir. Usually my first few turns after skinning a long way are a bit awkward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The snow at the entrance to the couloir did not look good and I expected the chunky snow to be difficult skiing. Thankfully it was so late in the day, the sun had had a long time to heat things up and the snow felt soft underneath. Near the top of the couloir was a punchy crust which would grab your skis if you weren’t careful when making turns. As we descended further the snow became noticeably softer and we could relax and make faster turns. The couloir offered a few good safety spots on the way down to wait for a partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/silver/looking-down.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking into the Couloir&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 2/3rds the way down, the couloir comes to a choke point then opens up to the runout apron. At this point the snow was very slushy and we could feel the afternoon heat warming everything up. We knew a short skin awaited us at the bottom of the couloir but hadn’t paid much attention to it. It turned out to be a bit of a slog. After traversing around back to the East a ways we lost the skin track and had to forage our way through the forest using our phone GPS. Eventually we met back up with the trail and we’re finally able to ski back to the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/silver/looking-back.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking back at Buffalo Mountain&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exhausted from the heat, we sat at the car and looked at the East face of Buffalo Mountain that we had just ascended. I couldn’t believe how warm it was in the mountains! All in all, a great day and a great line that every Colorado skier should check off.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dan</name></author><category term="skiing" /><summary type="html">The Silver Couloir is a popular ski line of the north east side of Buffalo Mountain in Summit County, CO. Famous for being included in the 50 Classic Ski Descents in North America, it offers skiers a chance to link themselves to the famous book with just a quick tour from the car.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trip Report: Skiing the Haute Route</title><link href="https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/04/24/what-i-learned-on-my-first-hut-to-hut-ski-tour.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trip Report: Skiing the Haute Route" /><published>2022-04-24T06:36:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-04-24T06:36:00-06:00</updated><id>https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/04/24/what-i-learned-on-my-first-hut-to-hut-ski-tour</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daniellytle.github.io/2022/04/24/what-i-learned-on-my-first-hut-to-hut-ski-tour.html">&lt;p&gt;The first time I heard about the Haute Route I had just gotten into ski touring. I was living in Denver, CO learning about avalanche safety and skiing powdery lines while gaining uphill fitness. It seemed like a dream trip for ski tourers and at the end of 2021 I decided to go for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Haute Route is a journey from Chamonix, France to Zermatt, Switzerland through some of the most incredible terrain on earth. Folks from all over make this journey through all seasons, hiking, skiing, even biking their way through the alps. Nights are spent at a variation of mountain huts situated along the route (we learned later that our guide snow-camped the route when he was 18).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-shakedown-day-and-gear&quot;&gt;The Shakedown Day and Gear&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day of the trip was a test. Our guide wanted to know did we have all the gear required to make the journey and did we know how to use it. We toured around the Grand Montets ski area just above the first glacier we would cross when we set off for Zermatt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/shakedown_day.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Shakedown Day&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We skinned hard uphill, learning later our guide had been pushing the pace to see how fast our group could move. To my surprise our group was very fit and capable and I found myself working hard to keep up most of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming from Colorado, I felt confident my experience at higher altitudes would bail me out of gear mishaps and pack weight. I soon realized the alps are very different from the rockies and the gear I had interpreted as optional was really essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ski Crampons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience when the slope got icy you made do. Coloradans love proper skinning technique and don’t like to rely on metal blades to secure footing when heading up an icy slope. The Alps were a whole new level of ice however, and when doing kick turns on a steep slope above a ravine or crevasse I was grateful the guide made me purchase them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merino Wool Base Layers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t have much backpacking experience before this trip and after spending a few days in a sweat soaked polyester t-shirt I understood why many long range tourers only trust this material. I don’t think I’ll ever head back out on a long trip with anything but merino wool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lightweight Pack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expecting to be skiing massive lines in deep snow I brought a long a large pack that had an avalanche airbag attached. I was proud that I had the extra safety measures in place. Looking back, I probably could’ve gone without it. The extra weight brought along with an airbag battery or canister is substantial and I received plenty of flak from my team over it. I couldn’t help but marvel at our guides pack and how tiny it looked compared to my monstrosity. In hindsight I would’ve brought a lightweight pack, with 2 pairs of socks, a merino wool baselayer and a single change of clothes for hut time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-1---argentiere-to-trient-hut&quot;&gt;Day 1 - Argentiere to Trient Hut&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/day-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Day 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started day one riding the Grand Montets lift as high as we could then headed for the Col du Passon. Booting up the Col was our first crampons-on bootpack and we roped up before ascending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/col_du_passon.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Col du passon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here we made our way across the Glacier du Tour towards the next Col that would take us across the border into Switzerland. What started as a ecstatic ski descent turned into a hot slog across the flat glacier. I striped down to my t-shirt and began eating snow to cool off. It’s worth mentioning how bright the glacier environment is. I barely got by with casual sunglasses but would certainly comeback with full side covered glasses or proper “Glacier glasses”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiking up the next Col we were rewarded with a fun ski descent and the first view of a mountain hut! A short skin and we were at the Trient Hut, a member of the Swiss mountain hut system. Below the Swiss flag flies the flag of the Canton (Valley Region) of Valais.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/trient_hut.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Trient Hut&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-bit-about-all-the-huts&quot;&gt;A bit about all the huts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few things were consistent in all our hut stays on the trip:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All huts had an in-house collection of Crocs for you to wear when inside the hut. We would arrive at each hut and immediately look for our Crocs. The earlier you arrive the better chance you have of finding ones that fit!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you arrived during the lunch hour, most huts offered a lunch options. I was introduced to Rösti, a heavy hashbrown dish that tasted amazing after a full day of skiing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dinner was included in your hut reservation and consisted of a three course experience: soup, main course, then a dessert. This was always and exciting time as the hut was buzzing with activity and groups discussing plans for the next day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-2---trient-hut-to-praflueri-hut&quot;&gt;Day 2 - Trient Hut to Praflueri Hut&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/day-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Day 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morning starts at 5:30AM when the first headlamp clicks on and the mad dash to organize ones gear gets underway. We had been prepared for a critical early morning by our guide. Just beyond the Trient hut was a rocky bootpack bottleneck that can become seriously clogged by skiers heading east from the Trient hut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/morning-climb.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Climb up&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, our group was first to the base of the climb, with other groups scraping down the icy slope close behind. With bits of loose rock coming down around us, we scampered up the incline and headed down the valley into Champex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ski-down-champex.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking towards Champex&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Champex we took a taxi to Verbier and relaxed for a bit before taking the lift up toward where we would start out climb. After skinning up 2 Cols and a few wide glaciers we arrived at our extra credit opportunity, climbing the Rosablanche, which the group unanimously agreed to undertake. From the summit we could see the Matterhorn and Mont Blanc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/rosablanche.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Top of the Rosablanche&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here we had an easy ski down to the Praflueri hut, located down the valley. The snow was a bit crusty but the path was wide open and our group toughed through burning quads to shred the whole way to the hut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/skiing-to-praf.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Skiing down to Praflueri&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A much more vibrant hut greeted us at the bottom. The Praflueri hut is a privately owned hut (not in the official swiss system) and a more relaxed vibe was welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/praf.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Praflueri hut&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-3---praflueri-hut-to-dix-hut&quot;&gt;Day 3 - Praflueri Hut to Dix Hut&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a difficult day of traversing across icy slopes and through avalanche debris. After climbing the first Col we’d hang along the high slopes above Lac du dix until we would climb up and out onto the glacier towards the Dix hut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/day-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Day 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefits of a lightweight pack were amplified as the group did multiple hours traversing almost only on skiers right. A very steep skin at the southern end of the lake was welcome as at least it would inflict balanced suffering on the body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were lucky to have great weather, each day we awoke to blue skies and warm temperatures. Towards midday the snow turned slushy and being on the glacier felt like being in a microwave. The final climb to the Dix hut is especially demoralizing as the route curls almost directly beneath the hut. The group was very relieved to drop our packs after a short but tricky day of touring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/dix-hut.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Dix Hut&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Securing a premium picnic table on the deck, our group enjoyed a Rösti (my first of many) and a few beers. The view was maybe too spectacular as I had to fully close my hood to prevent all the glacial light from overwhelming me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/hut-eating.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Dix Hut Eating&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-4---dix-hut-to-vignettes-hut&quot;&gt;Day 4 - Dix Hut to Vignettes Hut&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our fourth day was short but challenging. Our guide told us we were entering some of the more serious glaciated areas and we would rope up on the ascents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/day-4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Day 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We split into two rope groups of 4 and 3. It was tricky keeping the right amount of slack between skiers while switchbacking up the slope but our group got the hang of it quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/roped-up.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Rope Work&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we had come over the steepest bits we climbed to the Pigne d’Arolla which offered great views of the valley and an even closer view of the Matterhorn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pigne.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Pigne d&apos;Arolla&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here we had a tricky ski down to the Vignettes hut. There was a lot of crevassed terrain and a very narrow/rocky path through it all. Our group took it slow and smooth and was quickly looking at one of the more dramatic huts in the world. Perched near a sheer drop on both sides, the Vignettes hut is incredible to witness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/vignettes.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Vignettes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had arrived quite early and our legs still had a bit of juice in them so the group decided to unload our things then do a group ski down the slope to the north of the hut. The run was wide open and the snow was starting to soften. It felt crazy to do extra work that wasn’t needed for the route but the group was so excited to do a bit of pure skiing you didn’t think about it at all. I felt right back at home doing some “earn your turns” skiing, although something about going down then up is a little harder to swallow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/chill-ski.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Chill Ski&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dinner in the Vignettes hut was exciting as we had decided to go for Zermatt the next day. Some itineraries divert to the town of Arolla due to the conditions of the glaciers on the approach to Zermatt. Our guide had been very cautious and trusted his information that the way would be safe and our group could handle the risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out the massive ski touring race the Patrouille des glaciers was approaching and in preparation, the Swiss army had examined and marked the safe areas on the route down to Zermatt, the route the racers would be coming up on their way to Verbier. With this stroke of luck we were bound for Zermatt!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-5---vignettes-hut-to-zermatt&quot;&gt;Day 5 - Vignettes hut to Zermatt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day five was a fittingly epic final day to an epic trip. It involved three main bits: A skin to a reasonable Col, a long skin to a solid bootpack, then a long steady climb to our perch above Zermatt and the Matterhorn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/day-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Day 5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the fifth day our group was beginning to show signs of wear. I had a neat little rash on my shoulder from wearing a polyester shirt, a few had skins kept on by ski straps and bits of wire, a few poles were bent, and the blisters were starting to open up again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/over-the-hill.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Over the hill&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that washed away as we came over the crest of the Col near the Tete Blanche and saw the Matternhorn directly ahead. In the distance we could see red poles, driven into the snow by the Swiss army, directing the way down to Zermatt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/view-over-the-hill.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;View over the hill&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed great skiing down the glacier into Zermatt while making sure to stay close to the red poles that symbolized safety from crevasses. The snow was softening up and it seemed like the descent would never stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/skiing-down.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Skiing down&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually the snow ran out and we hit the dirt. From here we bootpacked to a road, which then led us to the Zermatt piste. Thankfully we still had a bit of elevation and were able to pole push our way to the base of Zermatt where we enjoyed a well deserved beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/bears.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Beers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m extremely thankful to our guide Mike and my group: Allis, Tom E, Tom J, Amicia, and Pete. It was hard work but they all made it an absolute pleasure. Now it’s back to Colorado to scrape all the snow left on the Rockies before the season ends!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dan</name></author><category term="trip-report" /><summary type="html">The first time I heard about the Haute Route I had just gotten into ski touring. I was living in Denver, CO learning about avalanche safety and skiing powdery lines while gaining uphill fitness. It seemed like a dream trip for ski tourers and at the end of 2021 I decided to go for it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://daniellytle.github.io/assets/img/shakedown_day.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://daniellytle.github.io/assets/img/shakedown_day.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sailing down the American East Coast, NYC to Daytona Beach</title><link href="https://daniellytle.github.io/2021/11/29/sailing-down-the-american-east-coast.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sailing down the American East Coast, NYC to Daytona Beach" /><published>2021-11-29T17:02:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-11-29T17:02:00-07:00</updated><id>https://daniellytle.github.io/2021/11/29/sailing-down-the-american-east-coast</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daniellytle.github.io/2021/11/29/sailing-down-the-american-east-coast.html">&lt;p&gt;The time between jobs is a great chance for a long adventure. In the fall of 2021 I set out from NYC on my sailboat bound for warmer climates. I had done a bit of research into route planning and passages by chatting with friends and finding other blogs similar to this one. In this post I’ll detail the route I took and interesting points of note from along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I waited a while to make this post so I don’t remember much from the voyage but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FxqqYmYuUlI&amp;amp;t=1s&quot;&gt;here is a summary video I made&lt;/a&gt; and the following sailing segments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 1: NYC to Cape May, NJ&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 2: Cape May, NJ to Ocean City, MD&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 3: Ocean City, MD to Norfolk, VA&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 4: Norfolk, VA to Waterside Marina&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 5: Waterside Marina to Dismal Swamp Welcome Center&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 6: Dismal Swamp Welcome Center to Alligator River&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 7: Alligator River to Neuse River&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 8: Neuse River to Morehead City, NC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 9: Morehead City, NC to Camp Lejune&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 10: Camp Lejune to Wrightsville Beach, NC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 11: Wrightsville Beach, NC to Charleston, SC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 12: Charleston, SC to Ashepoo River, SC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 13: Ashepoo River, SC to Port Royal, SC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 14: Port Royal, SC to Mayport, FL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 15: Mayport, FL to Marineland Marina, FL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 16: Marineland Marina, FL to Daytona Beach, FL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>dan</name></author><summary type="html">The time between jobs is a great chance for a long adventure. In the fall of 2021 I set out from NYC on my sailboat bound for warmer climates. I had done a bit of research into route planning and passages by chatting with friends and finding other blogs similar to this one. In this post I’ll detail the route I took and interesting points of note from along the way.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Making a DIY paddleboard rack for a sailboat</title><link href="https://daniellytle.github.io/2021/06/29/making-a-diy-sailboat-rack-for-surfboards-and-paddleboards.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making a DIY paddleboard rack for a sailboat" /><published>2021-06-29T22:01:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-06-29T22:01:00-06:00</updated><id>https://daniellytle.github.io/2021/06/29/making-a-diy-sailboat-rack-for-surfboards-and-paddleboards</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daniellytle.github.io/2021/06/29/making-a-diy-sailboat-rack-for-surfboards-and-paddleboards.html">&lt;p&gt;I was looking for an easy way to hold my paddleboard of to the side of my boat but couldn’t believe
how expensive the available options were. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Magma-Products-R10-626-Polished-Stainless/dp/B00MNQSHFE/ref=pd_lpo_2?pd_rd_i=B00MNQSHFE&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;This Magma surf rack holder&lt;/a&gt;
is nice and solid but $270? I figured I’d try to piece together a cheaper option and started looking for the bare pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this &lt;a href=&quot;amazon.com/gp/product/B086KVCCSR&quot;&gt;Garage roof SUP holder piece&lt;/a&gt; for around $30 and figured it wouldn’t be hard to attach it to the stanchions on
on the side of the boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/51zPj2ltm8L._AC_SL1001_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SUP piece&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I used two &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00TUNSR9Y&quot;&gt;SeaDog rail clamps&lt;/a&gt;
to connect the U-bend piece to the stanchions. The result was a solid paddleboard holder at a fraction of the price!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boat-rack-1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Boat SUP Rack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dan</name></author><summary type="html">I was looking for an easy way to hold my paddleboard of to the side of my boat but couldn’t believe how expensive the available options were. This Magma surf rack holder is nice and solid but $270? I figured I’d try to piece together a cheaper option and started looking for the bare pieces.</summary></entry></feed>