<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thebowenmethod.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://thebowenmethod.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-06-17T07:50:03-06:00</updated><id>https://thebowenmethod.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Bowen Method</title><subtitle>Write down three things you want to do, then do them</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Hammering Mount Shasta Through Avalanche Gulch</title><link href="https://thebowenmethod.com/2022/06/04/hammering-mount-shasta-through-avalanche-gulch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hammering Mount Shasta Through Avalanche Gulch" /><published>2022-06-04T21:41:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-06-04T21:41:00-06:00</updated><id>https://thebowenmethod.com/2022/06/04/hammering-mount-shasta-through-avalanche-gulch</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thebowenmethod.com/2022/06/04/hammering-mount-shasta-through-avalanche-gulch.html">&lt;p&gt;In 2017 I flew from Michigan to California to climb Mt. Shasta with my friend Matt. The plan was to camp at altitude to accelerate the aclimation process and do a summit push the next day. It was an ill fated expedition for myself as I woke up on summit day with a splitting headache and was sick at 9,000 ft. While I was happy to be back at the car after shuffling down the mountain at 5am, it’s weighed on me for a while now. After building some mountaineering skills and fitness over the last few years I figured it was time to take another crack at one of Californias few 14ers and this time bring my skis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After doing the Haute Route, and reading about a guy who did a Mt Hood speed run in minimal clothing/gear I was sold on the fast and light technique. This meant forgoing the acclimation day and doing a 1 day summit push. This meant 7,000ft elevation gain but much less gear and fussing with said gear. I had done a gravel bike race 2 days prior in the area around Mt. Shasta, I figured that would count for a bit of acclimation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/shasta/IMG_1559.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Recon Hike&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured a recon hike the day before would give me a good idea of the conditions and spot where I would transition to my ski boots. Mt. Shasta has a few glaciers on it but the Avalanche Gulch Route which approaches the mountain from the South has none. After hiking up about 2 miles and chatting with a few other skiers coming down after their summit I felt pretty good about the conditions and settled in for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/shasta/IMG_1565.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wake Up Call&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my alarm went off at 2am I was really not in the mood. My twin air mattress felt like a Temperpedic and I layed there for a bit. Eventually I found the motivation to get moving and brave the brisk air outside. It was Monday morning and there wasn’t much activity at the trailhead. I set off alone up the trail and was feeling good. I had some tunes going and was in my soft running shoes making good time towards the ski boot transition point. I passed the Horse Camp hut and from this point could see a few headlamps high up on the mountain. These were people who had camped at the high altitude Lake Helen the night before and were pushing for the summit early in hopes of watching the sunrise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached the snow and began the skinning on the hard bumpy snow. I had figured this snow would grip like the Mt Hood skinning I had done recently and had chosen to leave my Ski Crampons at the car, as the slope pitched up I was slipping and sliding every other step. Cursing myself for not bringing this special tool that was exactly the thing I needed now, I was getting a bit worried about how the other 5-6k feet would go. Eventually the sloped pitched back down as I headed up towards Helen Lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just above Helen Lake I looked back to see the sun hit the valley below me and could just make out the headlamp of one climber heading up far behind me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pitch of the slope above Helen Lake quickly increased to an angle that would require boot crampons. While I stopped to transition and have a bite to eat the hiker below me caught up and I got to chat with him for a brief time. We would end up playing tag the rest of the ascent to the lower ridge, from there we would hike to the summit together. It was nice to have a companion for conversation and safety as well, these fleeting mountain friendships are special but usually over very soon, especially since he was purely on foot and I would be skiing down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming above the ridge I would meet a few climbers glissading down from the summit including the folks that witnessed the sunrise from the top. It was still early morning and the sliding must’ve been quite rough. We came up to “Misery Hill” and found a nearly dry proper switchback trail, the first of the entire climb (mostly the avalanche gulch hike is taken straight at the lower ridge). After Misery Hill we were a bit confused and consulted our maps as a few peaks are visible and it’s not clearly visible which is the true summit. Eventually we found our way North, passing near a gas vent close to the summit. The smell was very noticable and I began to think the encroaching headache was more due to sulfur inhalation than lack of oxygen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/shasta/IMG_1571.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alpine Gas Vent&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon we hooked around up the final ridge to the summit and enjoyed hazy mid morning views in every direction around northern California. Mt Shasta is incredible in it’s isolation from other large peaks and it felt like we were in a hot air balloon at 14,180 feet in the sky. It was 9:30am, I was pretty happy with my timing and wouldn’t have to worry about hurrying down the mountain. It was very windy at the summit and I didn’t like the way my skis on my back would catch the wind so my buddy and I exchanged summit pictures and parted ways to descend the mountain. He had a long way to climb/slide back to the trailhead and I had an exciting much anticipated ski line to choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/shasta/IMG_4929.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;At the summit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-ski-descent&quot;&gt;The Ski Descent&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the summit down to the lower ridge the conditions were rough. “Bulletproof” is a ski term I would ascribe to those high altitude conditions and I chattered my way down through the lower ridge chutes, grateful to be moving so quickly. Eventually I found my way West to smooth open slopes that had caught the sun earlier in the day. My quads certainly did not have the juice to do 6k of skiing continuously so I would find small rock patches to wait beneath to catch my breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/shasta/IMG_1587.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Heading down&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I had descended to the sweet spot altitude where the snow was soft and slushy and began to transition from safe skiing to party mode, much to the chagrin of the late morning hikers heading up the gulch. After cruising through maybe 2k of slush I was back at the end of the snow field where I had been at 5am that morning. My feet were grateful to be out of the ski boots and into my wide running shoes. Soon I was bounding down the trail towards the trailhead and a hearty lunch.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In 2017 I flew from Michigan to California to climb Mt. Shasta with my friend Matt. The plan was to camp at altitude to accelerate the aclimation process and do a summit push the next day. It was an ill fated expedition for myself as I woke up on summit day with a splitting headache and was sick at 9,000 ft. While I was happy to be back at the car after shuffling down the mountain at 5am, it’s weighed on me for a while now. After building some mountaineering skills and fitness over the last few years I figured it was time to take another crack at one of Californias few 14ers and this time bring my skis.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thebowenmethod.com/assets/img/shasta/IMG_1587.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://thebowenmethod.com/assets/img/shasta/IMG_1587.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Trip Report: Bikepacking 101, My First Overnight Tour</title><link href="https://thebowenmethod.com/2022/05/09/trip-report-bikepacking-101-my-first-overnight-bike-tour.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trip Report: Bikepacking 101, My First Overnight Tour" /><published>2022-05-09T16:19:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-05-09T16:19:00-06:00</updated><id>https://thebowenmethod.com/2022/05/09/trip-report-bikepacking-101-my-first-overnight-bike-tour</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thebowenmethod.com/2022/05/09/trip-report-bikepacking-101-my-first-overnight-bike-tour.html">&lt;p&gt;Something I’ve always liked about biking is how far you can go and by extension, how much you can see. It makes sense that the hot new activity these days is “bikepacking”, or carrying gear to do multi-day trips on bikes. My cousin Sarah Swallow (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/sarahjswallow/?hl=en&quot;&gt;@sarahjswallow&lt;/a&gt;) has been in the bikepacking world for years and has traveled the globe planning routes and even bootstraping entire bikepacking events. She inspired me to take a crack at it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plan was to get the necessary gear, do a bit of a trial run with it, then take off! I checked around on &lt;a href=&quot;bikepacking.com&quot;&gt;bikepacking.com&lt;/a&gt; for a route close by and found &lt;a href=&quot;https://bikepacking.com/routes/boulder-bikepacking-loop/&quot;&gt;The Boulder Bikepacking Weekender&lt;/a&gt;. I figured I could do it “From the door” as my buddy says, and head from my house in Denver 30 miles to the start of the route in Boulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;testing-out-the-gear&quot;&gt;Testing out the gear&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s totally worth doing test runs in new gear before you get deep into a spot where there’s no cell service, or shops, or cover. It’s never fun to do but I’ve been burned enough times that I know the worth of knowing what to expect from my gear. The biggest question mark in my mind for this trip was my sleep system. Would it be warm enough? Would it pack light enough? I had to do a test run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/bivvy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Backyard Bivvy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite nonstop train horns and street racing noise I managed to sleep relatively comfortably! I was very excited about the bivvy bag as it was so much lighter and smaller than a full tent. I felt happy with my setup and ready to try it out in the field. A few days later I packed up the rig and set off for boulder where I would begin climbing into the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/leaving-the-house.png&quot; alt=&quot;Leaving the house&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving the house, the bike didn’t feel very heavy. Eventually I would feel ever single kilo of it on a very climbing intensive route. All in all it was a somewhat light setup. Still fretting over a heavier-than-needed pack used in my Haute Route tour, I opted for only what I would absolutely need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After making the relaxed journey from Denver to Boulder which is about 30 miles on mostly bike path, I met up with my pal Peter who had agreed to ride with me up the first bits of the route. In Boulder, We stopped at Boxcar Coffee which clearly was one of the popular cyclist hangouts as the bike to person ratio seemed close to one. After watching the Sunday group rides take off we hopped on our bikes and headed west into the Canyon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-first-climb&quot;&gt;The First Climb&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heading West up Boulder canyon, the route then climbs up to the south to meetup with Flagstaff Road and then continues on the highway to another gravel road on the way to Nederland. I figured I would see where I was in the afternoon and make a call about where to camp. Peter was on high mountain bike, casually spinning up the steep incline while I ground hard in my lowest gear. It was then I realized, “I think this gearing might be a problem”. In bicycle climbing vernacular, there are two ways to do it, “Spinning” - pedaling quickly while in a very low gear, and “Grinding” - pedaling somewhat slowly in a higher gear (sometimes standing up out of the saddle). Usually it’s refreshing to do a bit of both, this gives different muscles a chance to tap in and out. I had thought my gearing was relatively well set up for climbing, but it was certainly no mountain bike gearing. For the rest of the trip I would have to do 10%-13% grade climbs at a very low RPM, gripping the handlebar to keep my leg pressing muscles seated on the bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After chatting with Peter a bit more about the route, I had decided to make some detours to avoid a busy highway in favor of more secluded gravel. Changing the route as you ride it is always a fun gamble. As always, I was fighting with my Garmin bike computer, and it did not like me trying to make changes while it was recording my activity. Peter said farewell where the route met Flagstaff road and immediately following his departure the going got tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/singletrack.png&quot; alt=&quot;Singletrack Trail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went from pushing my bike up steep grade roads to cursing while riding mountain bike single track. Each large stone I failed to dodge would catapult my rear into a standing position, as if the ground was yelling at me to get up and peddle harder. At one point I passed two dirtbikers whose presence should have alerted me to the condition of the road to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/trail-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Gnarly Trail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I was saved by a smooth gravel road which led me almost directly to Nederland and a pizza shop. After scarffing two slices and about a gallon of pepsi, I set off on the leg connecting Nederland to Ward (another funky Colorado mountain town loved by cyclists). Heading up to the West on Caribou road made me feel the weight of the bike. This steep dirt road steadily climbed and climbed until I could see snow drifts all around. After reaching the junction where I was too turn North it became clear that I would need to find an alternate route. Road 505 which headed north towards ward was full of snow and looked impassible (I was kicking myself as the seasonal conditions of this road were mentioned in the route report). After chatting with some late afternoon skiers getting ready to hit the slopes nearby I headed back down into Nederland to take the highway shoulder to Ward. It was getting late in the day and I knew I likely wouldn’t make it before dark. In Nederland I found Gordan Gulch campground close by and set off hoping to get there with plenty of daylight left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-first-night&quot;&gt;The First Night&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pulling into Gordan Gulch was a relief and I was excited to set up all my new equipment in the field. After setting out my bivvy and sleeping bag I started to boil up some water for dinner to realize I had forgotten my utensils! I was still hungry enough to chow down the mountain house beef stroganoff in any way I could think off. I ended up using the preservative packet inside that says “DO NOT EAT THIS” as a spoon. After packing up my food supplies I followed bear protocol by hanging my portable kitchen up over a tree branch. It felt like a bit of a hassle but I’m sure with time it’ll feel like second nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/camp.png&quot; alt=&quot;Camp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/camp-food.png&quot; alt=&quot;Camp Food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally I sleep on my side, which I’ve found difficult to accomplish in past camping experiences. Ultralight bikepacking certainly didn’t allow any luxuries that would make that possible. Once it got pretty dark I tucked in on my back and arranged the bug net so I could see the stars and breath fresh air. Some day I’ll be so tired that my body will give up and learn to conk out purely on my back Sleeping Beauty style but this was not that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was glad when the sun rose as it meant I could stop pretending to sleep and get moving again. The temperature had gotten below what I expected and I shivered in the 38 degree morning air. Packing up camp warmed me up in no time, I skipped the luxury of morning coffee as I didn’t feel the need but I can imagine on a longer trip it would be enough to continually get me out of bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting off my devices were charged and I was heading for home! I knew a long day awaited me but I was excited about the journey and my bed awaiting me in Denver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-two&quot;&gt;Day Two&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pulled into Ward, CO soon after departing and the town was still asleep. I’d heard it was a cyclists destination and could tell this was true by the big “Scratch Energy” banner on the side of the General Store, making it clear to cyclists “this is where you can buy your special candy”. I encountered some funky weather coming out of the West but even with a bit of hail the sun shining in the East kept me warm and positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/ward.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ward&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/ward-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ward 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pulled off the road to start a big gravel ascent up towards Gold Hill, another popular Boulder cyclist spot. I was again cursing my gear ratio as I grinded up 10-13% grades. Some might say an 800ft climb is the best way to jump start the legs and at the top I was happy and stoked to be sitting on top of a ton of elevation, ready to coast down to some luxuries in town. Little did I know the route still had one last surprise in store for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-switzerland-trail&quot;&gt;The Switzerland Trail&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d seen postcards that described Colorado as the “Switzerland” of the US. This is brilliant marketing and got me pumped to ride The Switzerland Trail, a 5-6 mile section of gravel heading down towards Boulder. Soon I was wishing I had brought a dirt bike. Smooth gravel bits were intersperced with large loose rocks and the kinds of stones that look baked into the dirt. I cursed and bounced along for nearly the whole trail then finished with a slower slow climb to a trailhead. Popping out into a parking lot full of ATVs and Jeeps getting ready to take on the Switzerland trail made me feel badass but I honestly would not go back there on anything less than a hardtail mountain bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/road.png&quot; alt=&quot;Switzerland Trail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I was back on smooth gravel then onto pavement. Now the huge burden from my heavy bike lay on my disc brakes and I hurtled down towards Boulder. My front brake would positively sing when I pulled it hard but I was too tired to care about that anymore and I stayed on the brakes as my bike sung out for Boulder canyon to hear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rolling-back-to-denver&quot;&gt;Rolling back to Denver&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Coke and a sandwich in Boulder was a massive pick me up and soon I was ready to head out onto the plains. The sun was shining bright and I knew this would be a toasty final 30 miles. The Route from Denver to Boulder is pretty good, the US-30 bikeway provides secluded paved path for most of it. I was happily rolling along until getting to the most gnarly section, a spot just north of Denver that requires a good amount of sidewalk / side-highway riding. I always underestimate how much I enjoy the seclusion of gravel roads and riding next to snarling F-350s made me fondly remember even the worst parts of the Switzerland Trail. Someday I’ll find a better route through that industrial northern Denver neighborhood. Pulling back onto the Cherry creek trail felt great and I savored the last few miles to home through Wash Park and eventually back to the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boulder-weekend/denver.png&quot; alt=&quot;Denver in the distance!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do as much as you can to know the route. I love figuring stuff out on the fly and being surprised by the beauty of things but I wished I would’ve brought a bit of a softer bike with lower gearing. If I’m being honest the best way for me to learn this lesson was to go on this trip. Plan 30% of things I’d like to say :).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="trip-report" /><category term="bikepacking" /><summary type="html">Something I’ve always liked about biking is how far you can go and by extension, how much you can see. It makes sense that the hot new activity these days is “bikepacking”, or carrying gear to do multi-day trips on bikes. My cousin Sarah Swallow (@sarahjswallow) has been in the bikepacking world for years and has traveled the globe planning routes and even bootstraping entire bikepacking events. She inspired me to take a crack at it!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thebowenmethod.com/assets/img/boulder-weekend/valley.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://thebowenmethod.com/assets/img/boulder-weekend/valley.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Trip Report: Spring Skiing the Silver Couloir</title><link href="https://thebowenmethod.com/2022/05/06/trip-report-spring-skiing-the-silver-couloir.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trip Report: Spring Skiing the Silver Couloir" /><published>2022-05-06T15:39:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-05-06T15:39:00-06:00</updated><id>https://thebowenmethod.com/2022/05/06/trip-report-spring-skiing-the-silver-couloir</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thebowenmethod.com/2022/05/06/trip-report-spring-skiing-the-silver-couloir.html">&lt;p&gt;The Silver Couloir is a popular ski line of the north east side of Buffalo Mountain in Summit County, CO. Famous for being included in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.50classicskidescents.com/&quot;&gt;50 Classic Ski Descents in North America&lt;/a&gt;, it offers skiers a chance to link themselves to the famous book with just a quick tour from the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/silver/silver-gpx.png&quot; alt=&quot;Silver Couloir Route&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last Saturday in April had offered perfect weather: bluebird skies and warm temperatures. Knowing this we had planned to get to the summit early before the snow warmed too much. Just when we were about to set off up the trail I realized I had forgotten my avy beacon back in Denver. I had carpooled with my friend Zach who agreed to wait until one of the sports shops in summit county opened and I could grab a beacon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 8:30am we were back at the trailhead and transmitting strong beacon signals. The skintrack wasted no time getting up the east side of buffalo mountain and soon we were skinning up steep switchbacks nearing the treeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/silver/treeline.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Treeline&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about an hour of ascent we had reached treeline and were out on the east face of Buffalo Mountain. The view of Summit County was incredible and we could see the ski runs of Keystone and the soaring peaks of Grays and Torreys across the valley. We had plenty of company as it was the perfect weekend to ski the Silver Couloir. We met splitboarders, a guy in alpine boots, and a couple on their third date (All normal for a Colorado classic).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/silver/open.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Open&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the skinning leveled off we cruised all the way to the summit, unknowingly we had cruised right past the entrance to the couloir. It was nice to hang for a bit at the summit, get a bite to eat, then have a short warm up ski before dropping into the couloir. Usually my first few turns after skinning a long way are a bit awkward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The snow at the entrance to the couloir did not look good and I expected the chunky snow to be difficult skiing. Thankfully it was so late in the day, the sun had had a long time to heat things up and the snow felt soft underneath. Near the top of the couloir was a punchy crust which would grab your skis if you weren’t careful when making turns. As we descended further the snow became noticeably softer and we could relax and make faster turns. The couloir offered a few good safety spots on the way down to wait for a partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/silver/looking-down.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking into the Couloir&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 2/3rds the way down, the couloir comes to a choke point then opens up to the runout apron. At this point the snow was very slushy and we could feel the afternoon heat warming everything up. We knew a short skin awaited us at the bottom of the couloir but hadn’t paid much attention to it. It turned out to be a bit of a slog. After traversing around back to the East a ways we lost the skin track and had to forage our way through the forest using our phone GPS. Eventually we met back up with the trail and we’re finally able to ski back to the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/silver/looking-back.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking back at Buffalo Mountain&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exhausted from the heat, we sat at the car and looked at the East face of Buffalo Mountain that we had just ascended. I couldn’t believe how warm it was in the mountains! All in all, a great day and a great line that every Colorado skier should check off.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="skiing" /><summary type="html">The Silver Couloir is a popular ski line of the north east side of Buffalo Mountain in Summit County, CO. Famous for being included in the 50 Classic Ski Descents in North America, it offers skiers a chance to link themselves to the famous book with just a quick tour from the car.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trip Report: Skiing the Haute Route</title><link href="https://thebowenmethod.com/2022/04/24/what-i-learned-on-my-first-hut-to-hut-ski-tour.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trip Report: Skiing the Haute Route" /><published>2022-04-24T06:36:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-04-24T06:36:00-06:00</updated><id>https://thebowenmethod.com/2022/04/24/what-i-learned-on-my-first-hut-to-hut-ski-tour</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thebowenmethod.com/2022/04/24/what-i-learned-on-my-first-hut-to-hut-ski-tour.html">&lt;p&gt;The first time I heard about the Haute Route I had just gotten into ski touring. I was living in Denver, CO learning about avalanche safety and skiing powdery lines while gaining uphill fitness. It seemed like a dream trip for ski tourers and at the end of 2021 I decided to go for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Haute Route is a journey from Chamonix, France to Zermatt, Switzerland through some of the most incredible terrain on earth. Folks from all over make this journey through all seasons, hiking, skiing, even biking their way through the alps. Nights are spent at a variation of mountain huts situated along the route (we learned later that our guide snow-camped the route when he was 18).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-shakedown-day-and-gear&quot;&gt;The Shakedown Day and Gear&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day of the trip was a test. Our guide wanted to know did we have all the gear required to make the journey and did we know how to use it. We toured around the Grand Montets ski area just above the first glacier we would cross when we set off for Zermatt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/shakedown_day.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Shakedown Day&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We skinned hard uphill, learning later our guide had been pushing the pace to see how fast our group could move. To my surprise our group was very fit and capable and I found myself working hard to keep up most of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming from Colorado, I felt confident my experience at higher altitudes would bail me out of gear mishaps and pack weight. I soon realized the alps are very different from the rockies and the gear I had interpreted as optional was really essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ski Crampons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience when the slope got icy you made do. Coloradans love proper skinning technique and don’t like to rely on metal blades to secure footing when heading up an icy slope. The Alps were a whole new level of ice however, and when doing kick turns on a steep slope above a ravine or crevasse I was grateful the guide made me purchase them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merino Wool Base Layers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t have much backpacking experience before this trip and after spending a few days in a sweat soaked polyester t-shirt I understood why many long range tourers only trust this material. I don’t think I’ll ever head back out on a long trip with anything but merino wool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lightweight Pack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expecting to be skiing massive lines in deep snow I brought a long a large pack that had an avalanche airbag attached. I was proud that I had the extra safety measures in place. Looking back, I probably could’ve gone without it. The extra weight brought along with an airbag battery or canister is substantial and I received plenty of flak from my team over it. I couldn’t help but marvel at our guides pack and how tiny it looked compared to my monstrosity. In hindsight I would’ve brought a lightweight pack, with 2 pairs of socks, a merino wool baselayer and a single change of clothes for hut time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-1---argentiere-to-trient-hut&quot;&gt;Day 1 - Argentiere to Trient Hut&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/day-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Day 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started day one riding the Grand Montets lift as high as we could then headed for the Col du Passon. Booting up the Col was our first crampons-on bootpack and we roped up before ascending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/col_du_passon.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Col du passon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here we made our way across the Glacier du Tour towards the next Col that would take us across the border into Switzerland. What started as a ecstatic ski descent turned into a hot slog across the flat glacier. I striped down to my t-shirt and began eating snow to cool off. It’s worth mentioning how bright the glacier environment is. I barely got by with casual sunglasses but would certainly comeback with full side covered glasses or proper “Glacier glasses”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiking up the next Col we were rewarded with a fun ski descent and the first view of a mountain hut! A short skin and we were at the Trient Hut, a member of the Swiss mountain hut system. Below the Swiss flag flies the flag of the Canton (Valley Region) of Valais.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/trient_hut.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Trient Hut&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-bit-about-all-the-huts&quot;&gt;A bit about all the huts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few things were consistent in all our hut stays on the trip:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All huts had an in-house collection of Crocs for you to wear when inside the hut. We would arrive at each hut and immediately look for our Crocs. The earlier you arrive the better chance you have of finding ones that fit!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you arrived during the lunch hour, most huts offered a lunch options. I was introduced to Rösti, a heavy hashbrown dish that tasted amazing after a full day of skiing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dinner was included in your hut reservation and consisted of a three course experience: soup, main course, then a dessert. This was always and exciting time as the hut was buzzing with activity and groups discussing plans for the next day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-2---trient-hut-to-praflueri-hut&quot;&gt;Day 2 - Trient Hut to Praflueri Hut&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/day-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Day 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morning starts at 5:30AM when the first headlamp clicks on and the mad dash to organize ones gear gets underway. We had been prepared for a critical early morning by our guide. Just beyond the Trient hut was a rocky bootpack bottleneck that can become seriously clogged by skiers heading east from the Trient hut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/morning-climb.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Climb up&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, our group was first to the base of the climb, with other groups scraping down the icy slope close behind. With bits of loose rock coming down around us, we scampered up the incline and headed down the valley into Champex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ski-down-champex.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking towards Champex&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Champex we took a taxi to Verbier and relaxed for a bit before taking the lift up toward where we would start out climb. After skinning up 2 Cols and a few wide glaciers we arrived at our extra credit opportunity, climbing the Rosablanche, which the group unanimously agreed to undertake. From the summit we could see the Matterhorn and Mont Blanc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/rosablanche.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Top of the Rosablanche&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here we had an easy ski down to the Praflueri hut, located down the valley. The snow was a bit crusty but the path was wide open and our group toughed through burning quads to shred the whole way to the hut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/skiing-to-praf.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Skiing down to Praflueri&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A much more vibrant hut greeted us at the bottom. The Praflueri hut is a privately owned hut (not in the official swiss system) and a more relaxed vibe was welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/praf.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Praflueri hut&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-3---praflueri-hut-to-dix-hut&quot;&gt;Day 3 - Praflueri Hut to Dix Hut&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a difficult day of traversing across icy slopes and through avalanche debris. After climbing the first Col we’d hang along the high slopes above Lac du dix until we would climb up and out onto the glacier towards the Dix hut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/day-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Day 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefits of a lightweight pack were amplified as the group did multiple hours traversing almost only on skiers right. A very steep skin at the southern end of the lake was welcome as at least it would inflict balanced suffering on the body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were lucky to have great weather, each day we awoke to blue skies and warm temperatures. Towards midday the snow turned slushy and being on the glacier felt like being in a microwave. The final climb to the Dix hut is especially demoralizing as the route curls almost directly beneath the hut. The group was very relieved to drop our packs after a short but tricky day of touring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/dix-hut.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Dix Hut&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Securing a premium picnic table on the deck, our group enjoyed a Rösti (my first of many) and a few beers. The view was maybe too spectacular as I had to fully close my hood to prevent all the glacial light from overwhelming me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/hut-eating.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Dix Hut Eating&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-4---dix-hut-to-vignettes-hut&quot;&gt;Day 4 - Dix Hut to Vignettes Hut&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our fourth day was short but challenging. Our guide told us we were entering some of the more serious glaciated areas and we would rope up on the ascents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/day-4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Day 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We split into two rope groups of 4 and 3. It was tricky keeping the right amount of slack between skiers while switchbacking up the slope but our group got the hang of it quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/roped-up.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Rope Work&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we had come over the steepest bits we climbed to the Pigne d’Arolla which offered great views of the valley and an even closer view of the Matterhorn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pigne.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Pigne d'Arolla&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here we had a tricky ski down to the Vignettes hut. There was a lot of crevassed terrain and a very narrow/rocky path through it all. Our group took it slow and smooth and was quickly looking at one of the more dramatic huts in the world. Perched near a sheer drop on both sides, the Vignettes hut is incredible to witness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/vignettes.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Vignettes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had arrived quite early and our legs still had a bit of juice in them so the group decided to unload our things then do a group ski down the slope to the north of the hut. The run was wide open and the snow was starting to soften. It felt crazy to do extra work that wasn’t needed for the route but the group was so excited to do a bit of pure skiing you didn’t think about it at all. I felt right back at home doing some “earn your turns” skiing, although something about going down then up is a little harder to swallow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/chill-ski.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Chill Ski&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dinner in the Vignettes hut was exciting as we had decided to go for Zermatt the next day. Some itineraries divert to the town of Arolla due to the conditions of the glaciers on the approach to Zermatt. Our guide had been very cautious and trusted his information that the way would be safe and our group could handle the risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out the massive ski touring race the Patrouille des glaciers was approaching and in preparation, the Swiss army had examined and marked the safe areas on the route down to Zermatt, the route the racers would be coming up on their way to Verbier. With this stroke of luck we were bound for Zermatt!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-5---vignettes-hut-to-zermatt&quot;&gt;Day 5 - Vignettes hut to Zermatt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day five was a fittingly epic final day to an epic trip. It involved three main bits: A skin to a reasonable Col, a long skin to a solid bootpack, then a long steady climb to our perch above Zermatt and the Matterhorn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/day-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Day 5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the fifth day our group was beginning to show signs of wear. I had a neat little rash on my shoulder from wearing a polyester shirt, a few had skins kept on by ski straps and bits of wire, a few poles were bent, and the blisters were starting to open up again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/over-the-hill.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Over the hill&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that washed away as we came over the crest of the Col near the Tete Blanche and saw the Matternhorn directly ahead. In the distance we could see red poles, driven into the snow by the Swiss army, directing the way down to Zermatt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/view-over-the-hill.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;View over the hill&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed great skiing down the glacier into Zermatt while making sure to stay close to the red poles that symbolized safety from crevasses. The snow was softening up and it seemed like the descent would never stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/skiing-down.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Skiing down&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually the snow ran out and we hit the dirt. From here we bootpacked to a road, which then led us to the Zermatt piste. Thankfully we still had a bit of elevation and were able to pole push our way to the base of Zermatt where we enjoyed a well deserved beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/bears.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Beers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m extremely thankful to our guide Mike and my group: Allis, Tom E, Tom J, Amicia, and Pete. It was hard work but they all made it an absolute pleasure. Now it’s back to Colorado to scrape all the snow left on the Rockies before the season ends!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="trip-report" /><summary type="html">The first time I heard about the Haute Route I had just gotten into ski touring. I was living in Denver, CO learning about avalanche safety and skiing powdery lines while gaining uphill fitness. It seemed like a dream trip for ski tourers and at the end of 2021 I decided to go for it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thebowenmethod.com/assets/img/shakedown_day.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://thebowenmethod.com/assets/img/shakedown_day.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sailing down the American East Coast, NYC to Daytona Beach</title><link href="https://thebowenmethod.com/2021/11/29/sailing-down-the-american-east-coast.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sailing down the American East Coast, NYC to Daytona Beach" /><published>2021-11-29T17:02:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-11-29T17:02:00-07:00</updated><id>https://thebowenmethod.com/2021/11/29/sailing-down-the-american-east-coast</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thebowenmethod.com/2021/11/29/sailing-down-the-american-east-coast.html">&lt;p&gt;The time between jobs is a great chance for a long adventure. In the fall of 2021 I set out from NYC on my sailboat bound for warmer climates. I had done a bit of research into route planning and passages by chatting with friends and finding other blogs similar to this one. In this post I’ll detail the route I took and interesting points of note from along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I waited a while to make this post so I don’t remember much from the voyage but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FxqqYmYuUlI&amp;amp;t=1s&quot;&gt;here is a summary video I made&lt;/a&gt; and the following sailing segments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 1: NYC to Cape May, NJ&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 2: Cape May, NJ to Ocean City, MD&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 3: Ocean City, MD to Norfolk, VA&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 4: Norfolk, VA to Waterside Marina&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 5: Waterside Marina to Dismal Swamp Welcome Center&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 6: Dismal Swamp Welcome Center to Alligator River&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 7: Alligator River to Neuse River&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 8: Neuse River to Morehead City, NC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 9: Morehead City, NC to Camp Lejune&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 10: Camp Lejune to Wrightsville Beach, NC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 11: Wrightsville Beach, NC to Charleston, SC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 12: Charleston, SC to Ashepoo River, SC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 13: Ashepoo River, SC to Port Royal, SC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 14: Port Royal, SC to Mayport, FL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 15: Mayport, FL to Marineland Marina, FL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leg 16: Marineland Marina, FL to Daytona Beach, FL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The time between jobs is a great chance for a long adventure. In the fall of 2021 I set out from NYC on my sailboat bound for warmer climates. I had done a bit of research into route planning and passages by chatting with friends and finding other blogs similar to this one. In this post I’ll detail the route I took and interesting points of note from along the way.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Making a DIY paddleboard rack for a sailboat</title><link href="https://thebowenmethod.com/2021/06/29/making-a-diy-sailboat-rack-for-surfboards-and-paddleboards.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making a DIY paddleboard rack for a sailboat" /><published>2021-06-29T22:01:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-06-29T22:01:00-06:00</updated><id>https://thebowenmethod.com/2021/06/29/making-a-diy-sailboat-rack-for-surfboards-and-paddleboards</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thebowenmethod.com/2021/06/29/making-a-diy-sailboat-rack-for-surfboards-and-paddleboards.html">&lt;p&gt;I was looking for an easy way to hold my paddleboard of to the side of my boat but couldn’t believe
how expensive the available options were. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Magma-Products-R10-626-Polished-Stainless/dp/B00MNQSHFE/ref=pd_lpo_2?pd_rd_i=B00MNQSHFE&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;This Magma surf rack holder&lt;/a&gt;
is nice and solid but $270? I figured I’d try to piece together a cheaper option and started looking for the bare pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this &lt;a href=&quot;amazon.com/gp/product/B086KVCCSR&quot;&gt;Garage roof SUP holder piece&lt;/a&gt; for around $30 and figured it wouldn’t be hard to attach it to the stanchions on
on the side of the boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/51zPj2ltm8L._AC_SL1001_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SUP piece&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I used two &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00TUNSR9Y&quot;&gt;SeaDog rail clamps&lt;/a&gt;
to connect the U-bend piece to the stanchions. The result was a solid paddleboard holder at a fraction of the price!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/boat-rack-1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Boat SUP Rack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I was looking for an easy way to hold my paddleboard of to the side of my boat but couldn’t believe how expensive the available options were. This Magma surf rack holder is nice and solid but $270? I figured I’d try to piece together a cheaper option and started looking for the bare pieces.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">6 Month Ironman Training Plan with Google Calendar Import</title><link href="https://thebowenmethod.com/writing/2019/08/03/6-month-ironman-training-plan-google-calendar-compatible.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="6 Month Ironman Training Plan with Google Calendar Import" /><published>2019-08-03T10:18:55-06:00</published><updated>2019-08-03T10:18:55-06:00</updated><id>https://thebowenmethod.com/writing/2019/08/03/6-month-ironman-training-plan-google-calendar-compatible</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thebowenmethod.com/writing/2019/08/03/6-month-ironman-training-plan-google-calendar-compatible.html">&lt;p&gt;Here is the 220triathlon.com full distance training plan in csv format for Google Calendar import. I have it set to dates ending on November 2, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/6-month-ironman-training-plan.csv&quot;&gt;CSV Plan File&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.220triathlon.com/downloads/6monthIronmanTrainingPlan.pdf&quot;&gt;Original Plan Document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">Here is the 220triathlon.com full distance training plan in csv format for Google Calendar import. I have it set to dates ending on November 2, 2019.</summary></entry></feed>